本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视制作
更多字幕 影视 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
我们撑不下去了  长官!
We can't hold out much longer, sir!
准将  立刻撤退!
General Hummel, you've gotta get us outta here now!
我不会让你们失望的  我不会的  孩子们
I won't let you down. I won't let you down, son.
还要等多久?  长官!  我们已伤亡十五名!
Goddamn it, sir! How long do we have to wait? I've lost 15 men already!
敌方攻势凌厉!
Sir, they're lightin' us up like a firestorm!
我是汉默  快救我手下!
This is General Hummel. You gotta get my men outta there!
我们不准进入敌区
We don't have clearance to go behind enemy lines, sir.
他们不会来救我们了  对不对  长官?
They're not coming for us, are they, sir?
众议院和特别军委会的诸公们
Congressman Weaver and esteemed members of the Special Armed Services Committee.
我来此是要抗议不平之事
I come before you to protest a grave injustice.
一切必须要停止
It has to stop.
爱妻  芭芭拉汉默
我好想你
I miss you so much.
有件事我一定要去做  芭芭拉
There's something I've gotta do, Barb.
那是在你生前我所办不到的
Something I couldn't do while you were here.
我试过  什么方法都试过了
I tried. You know I tried everything.
但我仍然不能唤起他们的注意
And I still don't have their attention.
希望这次会有用
Let's hope this elevates their thinking.
但无论发生什么事...
But whatever happens...
请你不要瞧不起我
please don't think less of me.
海军军火库
陆战队
Marine.
通知安全士官  汉默将军来此巡视安检措施
Inform the garrison C.O that General Hummel's coming on board with a security inspection team.
遵命长官  您的访视是我们的荣幸
Yes, sir. Sir, it's an honor having you, sir.
我拿到通行证了  麻醉针失效前我们有三十分钟可行动
I got the access card. We've got 30 minutes 'til those darts wear off.
快点!
Move it!
通行证  长官
The access card, sir.
开始行动
Let's do it.
军火库例行检查
2400 magazine check.
-外头雨下得真大!  -请你验明我的身份
-Man, it's wet out there!  -Check me through, will ya?
清除!
Clear!
-少校!  我要十六枚  -动作快点!
-I want 16, Major!  -Move it!
撤退!  锁上门!
Evac! Seal the door!
-不!  -锁门!  快锁门!
-No!  -Come on, man!  Seal it!
-不!  -锁门!
-No!  -Seal it!
让我出去!  天啊!
Let me outta here! Oh, God! Let me outta here! Oh, God!
放我出去!
Let me out! Let me out!
撤退!  快走  快离开这里!
Clear out. Get outta here!
对不起
Sorry.
快走吧
Let's move out.
华盛顿  联邦调查局检验室
-你欠我五块钱了  -去你的
-That'll be five dollars, Isherwood.  -You suck.
你们实在是太闲了
You guys have too much time on your hands.
终于到了!  快拿给我  谢谢你菲尔!
Yes! She's here! Bring it to me now. Thank you, Phil!
干嘛寄到这儿?
What's that? Why'd you get it sent here?
卡萝不准  她认为花六百块来买张唱片是很蠢的事
Carla wouldn't approve. She thinks it's dumb to spend $600 on an L.P.
没错  何不花十三块买张CD呢?
Carla's right. Why don't you just spend $13 on a CD, man?
一是因为我是披头四迷
First of all, it's because I'm a Beatlemaniac.
二是唱片音质比较好
And second, these sound better.
可能很严重  有可能是沙林毒气
Could be serious. Could be sarin gas.
机场的警犬闻出包裹里有点不对劲...
A dog out of JFK caught a whiff of something in this package...
是寄往波士尼亚难民营的包裹
postmarked to a Bosnian refugee camp.
可能是洗洁精  也可能是沙林毒气
It could be detergent, or it could be sarin gas.
波士尼亚难民营?
Bosnian refugee camp?
美国境内有五十万的塞尔维亚人
Half a million Serbians reside in the U.S., Marvin.
塞尔维亚人不喜欢波士尼亚人
Serbians don't like Bosnians.
穿上防护衣
You guys wanna get suited up?
-蟑螂带了吗?  -带了
-You bring the cockroaches?  -Got 'em.
气闸已封闭  史丹利  你们可以开始了
We have air lock, Stanley. You're all set to go.
十月一日  九点钟
October 1, 0900 hours.
史丹利古斯比探员与受训探员马文...
Agent Stanley Goodspeed, Agent/Trainee Marvin Isherwood...
检视木箱
initiating exam of wooden crate.
怀疑内藏沙林毒气
Suspicion of sarin gas inside.
-毒气在-GB喷雾罐中
-Marvin, sarin is a...  -G.B. Aerosol.
没错
That is correct.
里面有些色情杂志
Now, let's see. We have some dirty magazines.
赤裸原始美女
Stone Age Cave Girls in the Raw.
变态  这看来可不太妙
Kinky. And, uh... Not a good sign.
你好  小洋娃娃  你看  史丹利
Hello, little baby doll. Lookit, Stan.
-史丹利  -马文  快住手!
-Hi there, Stanley.  -Marvin!  -Marvin, don't!
-怎么了  史丹利?  -拿开!  拿开!
-Hi, Stan.  -Shit! Move back! Move back!
抽气
I want the exhaust.
五十秒后抽光毒气  你们不会有事的
Hang on, guys. We'll have that room clear in 50 seconds! You're gonna be okay.
老天!
Jesus Christ!
坏消息之外  还有更糟的情况
Okay, I've got some bad news and some really bad news.
坏消息是毒气有强烈腐蚀性  它正在腐蚀我们的防护衣
The bad news is that the gas is corrosive and it's eating our suits.
它侵蚀到我的手套了
It's all over my hand, man!
更糟的是...
The really bad news...
这里面的炸药和毒气足够...
is there's enough C-4 explosive and poison gas to blow the whole chamber...
把整栋大楼的人都宰掉
and kill everybody in the building.
爆炸会很猛烈  所有人离开检验室！
Detonation too heavy.  -Everybody, out of the room now!
把我们密封在里面
Seal us inside.
洒水装置怎么了  隆纳?
Where are the sprinklers, Lonner?
硫酸开始腐蚀我的防护衣了
The acid's eating my su...It's eating my fucking suit! All right?
妈的!
Shit!
洒水冲洗我们!
Just wash us off!
怎么不洒水?
Where are my sprinklers?
我们正在设法  水压有点问题
We're working on it. It's coming. It's just a flow problem.
这问题可严重了
Well, that's a pretty big friggin' problem, Lonner.
快想办法!
Fix it now!
炸弹何时引爆?
We're working on it! How much time do you have on that detonator?
一分十秒后
A minute ten.
你看!
Look at this!
毒气就快被抽光了
We're gonna have the room clear.
叫他们立刻注射颠茄素
Tell 'em to take the atropine, now!
注射颠茄素
The atropine, Isherwood.
什么?
What?
水呢?  只剩一分钟!
Where's my water, Lonner? One minute!
马文  快注射颠茄素!
Marvin, the atropine, now!
在保护衣融化前注入心脏
Inject it in your heart before your suit melts.
该死!
Shit!
史丹利也要注射
Make him take his dose.
水怎么还不来?
Where's that water?
把它拿走!
Get that away from me!
快点菲尔  看在上帝的份上!  快弄好!
Come on, Phil, fix it for Christ's sake!
立刻注射颠茄素  史丹利!
Take the atropine now, Stan, for Christ's sake!
我们的麻烦大了
We're fucked.
毒剂开始混合了
The poison's mixing.
你们还等什么?  立刻把针筒插进心脏!
What the fuck are you waiting for, Stanley? You take the fucking needle now!
-妈的!  -还有四十秒!
-Fuck! Shit! Oh, fuck, shit!  -Forty seconds!
如果防护衣溶蚀掉...你们死了  我们也活不成！
If that suit melts...If you die, we all die!
先注射解药再拆弹！
Inject your heart and then diffuse the bomb!
快点  快注射!
Come on, just do it, Stan!
该死!  我会偏掉的  我什么都看不到!
Shit! What if I miss my heart? I can't see shit!
快动手!
Do it now!
你要我把这么大的针筒插进心脏?
Look how big this is. You want me to stick this into my heart?
你们疯了吗?
Are you fucking nuts?
来了!  来了!
The sprinkler's coming! It's coming!
水来了!
Okay, here we go, man!
正常运作了
Sprinkler activated.
还剩几秒?
How much time left?
二十秒!
Twenty seconds!
来不及了
We're not gonna make it.
十五秒
Fifteen.
快点
Oh, come on.
完成!
Clear!
快让我出来!
Get me the fuck out of this gas chamber!
我差点把针筒插到心脏里!
I almost stabbed myself in the heart with this thing.
-史丹利?  -亲爱的
-Stan?  -Hey, darlin'.
嗨  宝贝
Hi, baby.
我过了很有趣的一天
Here inside where I hide with my loneliness.
我也是一样
I had such an interesting day today.
好吧  对我来说很有趣的一天
Yeah, I had kind of an interesting day myself.
好吧  你先说吧
Oh, okay, you go first.
恐怖份子寄出一个小包裹  盒装...
Oh, just some terrorists decided to send a little care package, box of goodies...
必须在它炸毁整栋大楼前拆除
which had to be neutralized before blowing up the office.
所以我下午请假
So I took the rest of the day off.
回家喝点酒  弹弹吉他  好好休息
Glass of wine, little guitar. Just relaxing.
甜心  这是个疯狂又危险的世界
-I mean it, honey. The world is being Fed-Ex'd to hell on a handcart.
谁要是选择在这时候生儿育女...
I really believe that anyone who's even thinking about having a child in this world...
那都是件残酷的事
is coldly considering an act of cruelty.
我在胡言乱语  对不起
I know, I'm rambling, I'm complaining. I'm sorry.
你有什么事?
What's your news, baby?
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
什么?
I'm sorry?
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
真的?
Really?
真的
Yeah.
哇!
Wow!
你只会说"哇"吗?
Is that all you're gonna say, is "wow"?
你怀孕了?
You're pregnant?
三个礼拜
Three weeks.
你怎么知道?  我是说你怎么知道的?
How do you know? I mean, h-how do you know?
验孕剂显示出蓝色  我就去看医生了
Blue! Just turned blue so I went to the doctor.
你刚才说的不是认真的吧?
Well, you didn't mean what you just said, did you?
什么?
When?
你刚说生儿育女...
Uh, just right now when you were talking about bringing a child into the world...
是件残酷的事
and having it be an act of cruelty.
那是当时的念头
I meant it at the time.
史丹利  那是七秒前的事
Stanley, at the time? You said it seven and a half seconds ago.
天啊!
Well, gosh!
中间还发生很多事  我们甚至还没结婚呢
Kind of a lot's happened since then. Look, we're not even married.
真好笑  你正好提到重点
I know. It's funny you should mention that.
好笑?
It's funny?
-你爱我吗?  -我当然爱你
-Do you love me?  -Of course I love you.
很好
Good.
你肯娶我吗?
Will you marry me?
慢点  别操之过急
Whoa! Whoa! Wai... Hey, Marriage Police, pull over!
别闹了  史丹利  我正在向你求婚呢
Come on, Stanley. I'm proposing to you right now.
恶魔岛是史上最有名也最恐怖的监狱
The Rock is the most famous and was the most feared prison ever built.
真的从来没有人能逃狱?
Is it really true that there's never been an escape?
没错  1936年直到1963年监狱关闭前...
Ah, that's true. From 1936 until '63 when the prison closed...
总共有十四次逃狱事件
there were 14 attempts.
没有人能够活着逃上岸
No one is believed to have made it to shore, alive at least.
这里不准游客进入
No, uh, h-h-hey, hey, fellas. I'm sorry, but tourists are not allowed back here.
谁甩你  你管的着吗?
I don't really give a shit! Do you give a shit?
你们过来
Come here, fruity.
快点!
Move!
-小妹妹  玩的开心吗?  -开心
-Hey, girls? Hi. You all havin' a good time?  -Yeah.
帮我做件事好吗?
Will you do something for me?
这事很重要
It's really, it's really important.
我要你们去跟老师讲  请老师立刻带你们回船上
I need you to tell your teacher that you need to get back on the boat and go home right now.
各位  欢迎来到百老汇!
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Broadway!
这排囚室曾经关过...
This cell block housed...
美国最凶狠的匪徒
the most awesome scum in America.
女士们先生们  我  警备员巴布...
Ladies and gentlemen, I, Ranger Bob...
欢迎各位成为恶魔岛的阶下囚...
cordially invite you to become inmates of Alcatraz...
当然  只是暂时的
temporarily, of course.
大家排好!
On the line!
挺狭窄的吧?
Pretty tight quarters, aren't they, huh?
就像笼中兽一般  被关在里面几年...
Like being a caged animal. Spend a couple of years in there...
怎么了?  玩的不开心吗?
What's the matter, fellas? Something wrong with the tour?
游览已经结束了  巴布
The tour's over, Bob.
这算什么鬼游览啊?
What kind of fucked-up tour is this?
汉默将军  费上尉和戴上尉报到
General Hummel, Captains Frye and Darrow reporting, sir.
欢迎来到恶魔岛  各位
Welcome to The Rock, gentlemen.
把直升机降落在岛后方  开始部署
Land the choppers on the back side and deploy as planned.
-遵命  长官  -行动!
-Aye, aye, sir.  -Aye, aye, sir. Move out!
我没有佩枪许可
I'm not allowed to carry a gun.
你没有许可?  我有一把
Oh, you're not allowed to carry a gun? I got a goddamned gun.
早知道会这样  我就把枪带来了!
If I'd have known this was gonna happen, I'd have brought my motherfuckin' gun!
救命!
Help!
好了  各位  这里是我们的新家了
All right, gentlemen, this'll be our new home.
我们在这里成立指挥中心
Tom, I want my command center right here.
-行动  -是  长官
-I want Coms up.  -Roger that, sir.
卫星接收器摆在那儿  频率1600
Put the satellite over there. I wanna be up at 1600.
快
Let's move it.
系统启动
Systems up.
淋浴室有个地方可能被渗透
Possible penetration point in the shower room.
我们设置警告系统
We're setting anti-intrusion.
我带来个很特别的东西  长官
I brought a personal touch, sir.
一个震动侦测器
It's an anti-motion trembler device.
是特别订制的
It's custom-made.
没有人知道它的存在  更无法防范它
Nobody knows about it and nobody expects it.
它有什么用?
What's it do?
先用雷射光引诱敌人
We head-fake 'em with the laser beam.
只要触动这个震动侦测器  他们就完了
And then if they disturb Mr. Backup here, we own 'em.
各位被强制监禁在此  对此我感到很抱歉
Ladies and gentlemen, you're being detained against your will. For that, I apologize.
我们无意伤害你们
It is not our intention in any way to harm you.
只待我们的任务完成后  各位就会被立刻释放
You will not be detained one minute longer than is necessary for us to complete our mission.
立正!
Attention on deck!
各位请稍息
Stand easy, men.
毫无疑问我们正身处险境
Make no mistake about it, gentlemen, we are now in harm's way.
我和巴少校在68年越战时就是同袍了
For Major Baxter and I, this is the last campaign in a career datin' back to Tet '68.
同样韩上尉和柯中士...
Likewise for Captain Hendrix, Gunnery Sergeant Crisp...
跟随我在波斯湾战争中开始了他们的军旅生涯
who cut their teeth under my command in Desert Storm.
而费上尉和戴上尉
Captain Frye, Captain Darrow, this is my first operational situation with you and your men.
这是我首次与你们共事  你们的表现的确名不虚传
And I have to say, thus far your conduct reflects your reputations.
-谢谢  将军  -谢谢  长官
-Thank you, General.  -Thank you, sir.
我们占领此地的的行动沉着准确又大胆
We have achieved our position through poise, precision and audacity.
因此我们更要下定决心
To this we must now add resolve.
我们会被视为叛国者  重罪者..
We'll be branded as traitors, the gravest capital crime...
可能被判死刑
Punishable by death.
数百年前...
A couple hundred years ago...
华盛顿  杰佛逊等建国者...
a few guys named Washington, Jefferson and Adams...
也被英国视为叛国者
were branded as traitors by the British.
现在他们则被视为爱国者
And now they're called patriots.
历史将还我们清白
In time, so shall we.
如情况许可...
God willing, in less than 48 hours...
凭人质和VX毒气弹头  我们将在48小时内撤离
you will evacuate this island in gunships under cover of hostages and V.X. Gas warheads.
你们的目的地是没有引渡条约的国家
Your destination: A non-extradition treaty country.
每人将获得一百万美元的酬金
You will each be paid a fee of $1 million for services rendered.
但你们永远不能再踏上故乡的土地
But you can never again set foot on your native soil.
可以接受吗?
Can you live with that?
是  长官!
Yes, sir!
海军陆战队侦搜大队...
The men of Marine Force Recon...
被派往世界各地执行非法任务
are selected to carry out illegal operations throughout the world.
当他们战死异乡...
When they don't come home...
家人得到的只有谎言...
their families are told fairy tales about what happened to them...
没有任何补偿
and denied compensation.
这些谎言我已经忍受了一辈子!
Well, I have choked on these lies my entire career!
现在该是停止这些谎言了的时候了!
Well, here and now the lies stop!
上帝保佑你们  各就各位
God be with all of you. Man your positions, men.
华府  七点四十分
我是联邦调查局局长沃麦
This is FBI Director Womack.
局长  请听清楚
Director, be advised.
有81名  我重复
Eighty-one, I say again,
目前有81名人质在我手上
81 civilians are under my control as of this moment.
请将此列为最高机密
You are to take measures to assure this remains a need-to-know classified fact.
你是谁?
Who is this?
局长先生  你面临一个很严重的问题
Mr. Director, you have a very serious problem.
VX毒气导弹如箭在弦...
A battery of V.X. Gas rockets is presently deployed...
准备对旧金山湾区发出致命的一击
to deliver a highly lethal strike on the population of the San Francisco Bay area.
午夜时我将再以电话通知提出要求
I will call again at 0100 hours to state my demands.
你是什么人?
I want to know who I'm talking to.
海军陆战队法兰斯汉默准将  从恶魔岛发话
This is Brigadier General Francis X. Hummel, United States Marine Corps, from Alcatraz.
完毕!
Out!
我马上取消你的约会
I'll cancel your reservations.
联络五角大厦
Get the Pentagon.
通知旧金山办公室  看来恶魔岛又要开张了
And call the San Francisco office. It seems Alcatraz was just reopened.
五角大厦  11点58分
昨晚汉默将军带领一群彪悍但无害的陆战队员...
Last night General Hummel, using brutal but nonlethal force...
在安全士官的眼前偷走十五枚VX毒气导弹
under the guise of a security exercise, walked off with 15 V.X. Poison gas rockets.
过程中他的一名手下丧生
He lost one of his own men in the process.
汉默将军在越南的时候还是上校
That's General Hummel in Vietnam. I think he was a major at the time.
他在越南参与过三次任务...
Three tours in...
巴拿马  格瑞那达  和波斯湾战争
Vietnam, Panama, Grenada, Desert Storm.
荣获三枚紫星勋章  两枚银星勋章...
Three Purple Hearts, two Silver Stars...
还有国会荣誉勋章...
and the Congressional Medal of...
天啊!  这人是个英雄!
Jesus! This man is a hero!
我想"传奇英雄"应该是  比较恰当的形容词
Well, I think "legend" might be a better description, Mr. Sinclair.
我们可在他的英雄事迹上加上绑架和勒索了
Well, now we can add kidnapping and extortion to his list of accolades.
辛克莱先生  汉默将军是条好汉
Mr. Sinclair, General Hummel is a man of honor.
将军  是他
General, it's him.
法兰克  我是艾尔克拉玛
Frank, it's Al Kramer.
嗨艾尔  你好吗?
Hi, Al, how you doin'?
我不晓得  法兰克  你说呢
I don't know, Frank. Ah, why don't you tell me.
我这里有一堆忧虑的傢伙  法兰克
Got a lot of very, very worried people here, Frank.
我就直说吧
I'll come straight to the point.
在我的指挥之下有83名陆战队员为国捐躯
Eight-three Force Reconnaissance Marines have died under my various commands.
在寮国北部与中国南部牺牲了47名
Forty-seven in northern Laos and southern China.
中国南部?  我们从未承认曾派兵到中国去
Southern China? We never admitted we sent troops into China.
这是谁?  表明你的身份
Who is this? Identify yourself.
白宫幕僚长海顿·辛克莱
White House Chief of Staff Hayden Sinclair, General.
你今年几岁?  海顿·辛克莱幕僚长
How old are you, Chief of Staff Sinclair?
我33岁
I'm 33.
那么辛克莱先生  你根本就不知道我在说什么
Well, Mr. Sinclair, you've probably got no fucking idea what I'm talking about.
你九岁时我就在中国从事秘密活动...
By your ninth birthday, I was runnin' black ops into China...
歼灭了两百名敌军
and my men were responsible f-for over 200 enemy kills.
拿胶带帖住辛克莱先生的嘴
Al, put some rigging tape over Mr. Sinclair's mouth.
他在浪费我的时间
He's wasting my time.
你想继续说吗  法兰克?
Ah, you want to continue, Frank?
记得波斯湾战争中
Remember Operation Desert Storm?
CNN播出的精准导弹攻击报导吗?
Those surgical hits made by our smart bombs, covered so well on CNN?
那是因为我的手下在地面用雷射瞄准了目标
It was my men on the ground that made those hits possible by lasing the targets.
战后有二十人在巴格达壮烈牺牲
Twenty of them were left to rot outside Baghdad after the conflict ended.
他们的家人没有得到补偿
No benefits were paid to their families.
也没有获得任何勋章
No medals conferred.
他们为国捐躯却得不到军方的葬礼
These men died for their country, and they weren't even given a goddamn military burial.
情况已让人忍无可忍  你们从红海贸易公司...
The situation is unacceptable. You will transfer $100 million...
将一亿美元的转入我指定的帐户
from the Grand Cayman Red Sea Trading Company account to an account I designate.
这笔款项之中...
From these funds, reparations of $1 million will be paid...
83名军人遗属将各得一百万元
to each of the 83 marines' families.
至于余款我则会妥善散发
The rest of the funds I will disperse at my discretion.
我说得够清楚吗?
Do I make myself clear?
红海贸易公司?  那是什么?
Except for the Red Sea Trading Company. What is that?
请表明身份
Identify yourself.
我是联邦调查局局长沃麦将军
This is FBI Director Womack, General.
那是五角大厦非法军售的地下基金
It's a slush fund where the Pentagon keeps proceeds from illegal arms sales.
拜托  法兰克  这是最高机密
Jesus, Frank! This is classified information.
你们通知媒体  我就发射毒气导弹
You alert the media, I launch the gas.
你们拒不付钱  我也会发射毒气导弹
You refuse payment, I launch the gas.
到后天中午之前你们还有40小时把钱汇入
You've got 40 hours, 'til noon day after tomorrow to arrange transfer of the money.
我知道反制措施  你知  我也知  那一点也没用
I am aware of your countermeasure. You know and I know it doesn't stand a chance.
这是汉默从恶魔岛发话  通话完毕
Hummel from Alcatraz. Out.
我们必须查明人质的身份并分别通知他们的家属
All right. We have to identify the hostages and contact each of their families.
我要你们设法捏造理由  绝对不能泄密
Uh, tell 'em somethin'. Make up a story, and we've got to keep this undercover.
消息一旦泄露  旧金山将会一片混乱
If this comes out, the city of San Francisco will be in chaos. I am talking anarchy.
等等  等等
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
一枚VX毒气导弹...
What is the potential casualty rate...
潜在杀伤力有多大?
for a single rocket armed with V.X. Poison gas, General Peterson?
六至七吧
Sixty or seventy.
那还好嘛
Well, that's, that's not so bad.
单位是万  有七万人会死亡!
Thousand. Seventy thousand dead!
一汤匙毒气掉到地上  一百尺内人畜皆亡
One teaspoon of this hits the floor, it's lethal up to a hundred feet.
一汤匙毒气在空中引爆...
One teaspoon of this shit detonated in the atmosphere...
八条街以内的生物无一幸免
will kill every living organism in an eight-block radius.
明白了吗?
Get the point?
汉默说的反制措施是指什么呢?
Uh, what did Hummel mean by your countermeasure, General?
汽油燃烧弹能够把一般毒气烧光
Standard poison is countered by napalm. It burns it up, consumes it upon detonation.
但VX毒气导弹的设计...
Now, the problem with V.X. Poison gas is...
却是能抵抗汽油燃烧弹
that it's designed specifically to withstand napalm.
因此才会发展铝热剂  将军  请您继续
That's where, uh, thermite plasma comes in. General Peterson?
铝热剂燃烧弹的热度够高  足以消耗VX毒气
Thermite plasma incendiary systems can burn hot enough to consume V.X...
但是还在测试之中  还不能投入使用
but they're still in the test phase; it's not operational.
汉默一清二楚  我们在跟一个聪明的混蛋打交道呢
Hummel knows this. We are dealing with one smart son of a bitch.
在36小时内能不能把铝热剂准备好?
What's it gonna take to equip a flight of F-18s with thermite plasma...within the next 36 hours?
只有靠上帝了
An act of God.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
我们尽力而为
All right, we can try.
不过我建议将此列为辅助对策
But I strongly urge you to consider the use of this as a secondary initiative.
那我们必须采取主要对策了  上将
Then we have to go to our primary initiative. Uh, Admiral?
我要请特遣队队长安德逊来参与行动
Sir, I'd like to bring in our SEAL ground commander, Commander Anderson.
沃麦先生  你们局里最顶尖的生化专家是谁?
Mr. Womack, who is your best chemical/biological man?
有意思
Oh, that's interesting. Oh, yeah.
很吸引人
That's very compelling.
你喜欢我的辫子吗?
You like my pigtails?
你的辫子很俏皮  很性感
Oh, yeah, the pigtails are very naughty.
意大利奶油和桃红点心
Naughty. Naughty. Just the Amaretto cream with peach sorbet persuasion.
不会吧
This isn't happening.
别接电话
No, Stan, don't answer it.
-不会这样吧!  -别去接
-This isn't happening!  -No, just don't answer it. It's okay.
我一定得接  他们知道我在家
I have to. It's the office, baby. They know I'm home.
他们怎么会知道你在家呢?
How could they possibly know that you're home?
他们是联邦调查局
It's the FBI.
史丹利!
Stanley!
我是古斯比  对好吧
Goodspeed. Uh, yeah. O-Okay, yeah.
我十分钟后就下楼
I'll be, I'll be down, yeah, downstairs in ten minutes.
不行
No, you won't.
我得去旧金山
I have to go to San Francisco.
不  你不能去
No, you don't.
史丹利你不必去旧金山
Stanley, no, you do not have to go to San Francisco.
你在跟我开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding me right now?
你必须留下来  我们有些事要谈清楚
You need to stay here and talk to me about things.
我得走了  宝贝
I've got to go, baby.
我可是天主教徒  你明白这一点吗?
Oh! I am Catholic! Do you realize that?
我未婚怀孕  这对我来说问题可大了
I am pregnant and I am unmarried. And this causes a serious problem for me.
我真不能相信你
I cannot believe you.
不要
No, no.
我爱你  我会娶你
I love you. I will marry you.
我只是没有预期你会怀孕
I just didn't plan on this, that's all.
-你也来旧金山吧  -真的吗?
-Come to San Francisco.  -Really?
是啊  我相信这只是演习
Yeah, I'm sure it's just a training exercise.
我们住旅馆  点些香槟喝
Check into the hotel. Order up some champagne.
-继续我们的游戏?  -没错
-And we'll finish what we started?  -Exactly.
-你会娶我吗?  -当然
-Baby, you're gonna marry me?  -You know it.
你要娶我!
You're gonna marry me!
-亲爱的  很快就好了  -我得走了
-Oh, honey, come on. Just a really quick one.  -Oh, oh, I gotta go now.
在月圆之夜空降是行不通的
A nighttime airdrop incursion is out due to the full moon.
同样抢滩攻击也不行
Likewise a frontal seaside attack.
如果我们被汉默发现  他会发射导弹的
If we're compromised and shots are fired, Hummel might launch.
唯一可行的方法是从监狱内部攻击
Our only alternative is an attack from within the prison.
我们从监狱底部的隧道潜入中央地区
We penetrate the island through the tunnels under the prison buildings undetected...
那样我们就能由后方突击那些陆战队员
and emerge in its center; that way we can jump the marines from behind.
如果幸运的话
And if we're lucky...
也许不必动武就能夺回导弹
take their rocket positions without a shot fired.
我想知道...你研究过建筑蓝图吗?
I don't understand. You-you've studied the architectural plans?
没用的  恶魔岛重新翻修过多次
They're useless. Alcatraz has been ripped up and rebuilt for years.
-地底下就像迷宫  -毫无疑问
-Under there is a maze of shit.  -Well, there's no question, gentlemen.
我们需要熟悉那些地道的专家
We need firsthand intelligence of the tunnel systems.
前任典狱长呢?
So what about the former warden?
一九七九年就死了
Died in 1979.
我们联络过其他的狱警  都没用
All the guards we contacted were useless.
我知道有人帮的上忙
Um, there is someone who I think can help us.
这是为了国家安全
This is for the sake of national security.
33年前就是为了国家安全才会这样做
It's the sake of national security that got us here in the first place 33 years ago.
我就知道有一天我们会被反咬一口
I knew! I knew someday this would come back to bite us.
想都别想!  他不存在
Forget it! He does not exist.
他存在!
He does exist!
三十年来我们只是选择把他忘掉
We just chose to forget him for 30 years.
-我们把他关起来  -然后让他永不见天日
-We locked him up and threw away the key.  -Oh, and a lot of goddamn good it did us.
他曾从两座高安全措施的监狱逃出来
He broke out of two maximum-security prisons.
如果被他逃到街上...
And if he hits the streets...
他不会逃到街上的
He's not gonna hit the streets, Jim.
三十年前他确实是皇家特种部队的顶尖情报员
Thirty years ago he was a highly-trained SAS operative.
但现在他已跟我一样老了!
He is my age now, for Christ's sake!
我每晚还得爬起来上三次厕所呢
I have to get up three times a night to take a piss.
我们不能冒险放他出来
We can't risk letting him out.
他是专业的逃狱专家
He's a professional escape artist.
"莎士比亚"  "孙子兵法"
真帅的飞机啊
Neat, neat plane.
古斯比博士  我是沃麦
Dr. Goodspeed. James Womack.
-幸会  长官  -欢迎
-A pleasure to meet you, sir.  -Welcome.
你的评价极高
You come very highly recommended.
哥伦比亚大学学士  约翰霍普金斯大学硕士  博士
B.A. Columbia; M.A., PhD, Johns Hopkins.
生化毒物学博士
Biochemistry, toxicology.
很幸运  我热爱我的工作
Well, I'm one of those fortunate people who like my job, sir.
我七岁开始做化学实验  烧掉了自己的眉毛
Got my first chemistry set when I was seven. Blew my eyebrows off.
那只猫也此消失了  那时起就我爱上了这门学科
We never saw the cat again. Been into it ever since.
VX毒气你知道多少?
What do you know about V.X. Gas?
它是液态的  一九五二年除虫剂实验失败的产物
Liquid. Failed pesticide discovered by a mistake in 1952.
事实上就像香槟一样
Uh, actually, it's kind of like champagne that way.
修道士正在酿造白酒
The Franciscan monks thought they were making white wine.
无意中加入二氧化碳  然后香槟就诞生
Somehow the bottle carbonated. Voila! Champagne. And then the whole thing just...
VX毒气  古斯比博士
The gas, Dr. Goodspeed.
十分可怕  长官
It's very, very horrible, sir.
那东西是不应该被发明出来的
It's one of those things we wish we could disinvent.
这不是演习
This isn't a "train" exercise, is it?
没错  古斯比博士  这不是演习
No, Dr. Goodspeed, it's not a training exercise.
三十九号码头
FBI活动指挥中心
早安  局长
Good morning, Director.
这是厄尼·派斯顿  联邦调查局西岸负责人
This is Ernest Paxton, agent in charge of the West Coast operation.
这是古斯比博士
Dr. Goodspeed.
幸会
Pleasure to meet you.
幸会  先生
How do you do, sir?
今天真是耐人寻味  犯人已经在这里了
It's been a fairly interesting day so far. The prisoner's here. Shall we?
我的部下找不到他的档案  他到底是谁  长官?
Now, my boys, they haven't been able to find a file on this guy. Who is he anyway, sir?
他叫约翰·梅森  英国人...
His name is John Mason, a British national...
一九六二年被关进恶魔岛...
incarcerated on Alcatraz in 1962...
一九六三年逃狱
escaped in '63.
我以为没人能逃出恶魔岛  长官
I was under the impression that no one ever escaped Alcatraz, sir.
派斯顿  别顶嘴!
Paxton, don't argue!
这个人在美国和英国都没有身份
This man has no identity, not in the United States or Great Britain.
他不存在  懂吗?
He does not exist. Understand?
我只要知道他是怎么逃出恶魔岛的
I want one thing: How he escaped The Rock.
特别是他逃亡的路径
Specifically the route he took through the island's bowels.
文件准备好了
The papers are in order, sir.
我们准备完全赦免他
We're prepared to offer him a full pardon.
还有派斯顿  别对梅森来硬的  我太了解他了
And Paxton, no strong-arming Mason. I know him too well.
既然你了解他  为何你不亲自去问他呢?
Well, if you know him, then why don't you question him?
他记得我  我不希望他的愤怒搞砸整件事
No, he'll remember me. I don't want his anger clouding the issue.
我搞定他吧
All right, I'll take care of him.
梅森先生  我是负责人厄尼·派斯顿
Mr. Mason, I'm Special Agent in Charge, Ernest Paxton.
负责什么?  负责再多关我三十年?
In charge of what? Fucking me over for another three decades?
我不晓得你的过去  我之所以来此是因为...
I don't know anything about your previous matters. I'm here because...
我们面临一个特殊状况  我们认为你可能帮得上忙
a special situation exists that we feel you might be able to help us with.
那是什么?
Well, what might that be?
我被关得还比曼德拉还久
I've been in jail longer than Nelson Mandela.
也许你要我当总统?
So maybe you want me to run for president.
-不是  -可惜
-Not exactly.  -Mmm, a pity.
可惜  我好比阿格米达
I feel rather like Alcamenes.
-谁?  -阿格米达  在古希腊时代他被国王所囚禁
-Who?  -Alcamenes. He was imprisoned by his king in ancient Greece.
华特莱理爵士也有相同遭遇
Like Sir Walter Raleigh. The same fate.
詹姆士一世
James the First.
像你这样聪明的人该知道...
Even someone as bright as you must be aware that, uh...
历史会重演
there's a certain pattern emerging here.
还有亚历山大·索忍尼辛?
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn?
我知道  他是为共产党摇旗呐喊的傢伙
Yeah, I heard of him. Didn't he play hockey for the fuckin' Red Wings?
就是他
That's the chap.
我们干脆挑明吧老兄  我们都看对方不顺眼
Get this straight, pops. I don't like you any more than you like me.
但我来此是要向你提出合理的条件
But I'm here to make you a legitimate offer.
你到底想不想听?
You wanna hear what I have to say or not?
尽管说吧  亲爱的派斯顿
By all means, dear Paxton. By all means.
我们在一个你所熟悉的地方遇到了麻烦
We got a problem in a place that I think you know.
恶魔岛上有人质危机
There's a hostage situation on Alcatraz.
-人质?  -81名观光客
-Hostage?  -Eighty-one tourists.
恶魔岛变成观光胜地?
The Rock has become a tourist attraction?
废话少说  你对恶魔岛瞭如指掌
Why don't we cut the shit, huh? You know The Rock.
你从那里逃过狱
You broke out.
对  我成功了
Yes, successfully.
只要你肯帮我们这个忙
Yeah. So why don't you do yourself a favor while you're helpin' us?
趁还活着赶快出狱多好
I mean, it'd be nice to get out of jail while you're still vertical.
趁你那话儿还有用的时候
Hmm? While you got a little lead left in your pencil.
在我考虑条件期间...
While I'm considering your offer...
我要住进费蒙饭店的套房
I want a suite in the Fairmont Hotel.
我是来这里谈条件的
You know I'm here to cut you a deal.
我可不是来被你耍着玩的
I am not here to bend over and take it up the ass from you.
来  我给你个铜板
Here. Here's a quarter.
帮自己个忙吧
Do yourself a favor.
打电话通知你的律师  你得回到牢里
Call your lawyer. You're goin' back to jail.
-你要把他送回监狱?  -我哪里都不送他去
-Y-You're sending him back to jail?  -I'm not sending him anywhere.
我只是要让他好好想想
I'm just givin' him somethin' to think about.
我们没时间...
With all due respect, sir, I don't think we have time...
让他坐下来仔细想
for him to just sit around and think about it.
-是吗?  -对  古斯比说的对
-Oh, really?  -No, Goodspeed's right.
-你去和他谈  -我?
-You go talk to him.  -Me?
对
Yes.
-长官  我还不够资格呢  -你是FBI探员!
-Sir, I'm not qualified for that.  -You're an FBI agent!
-你的专长是什么?  -化学武器
-W-What is your specialty again?  -Chemical weapons.
这点提都别提!
Don't mention that!
-你要我说谎?  -没错  说谎
-You want me to lie?  -Yeah, lie.
我们剩不到二十四小时了  你就试试看吧
We got less than 24 hours. Give it a shot.
好吧
Okay.
我是联邦...
I'm an agent with the, uh, uh, F-Federal...
FBI的人
FBI. Uh...
我叫史丹利古斯比
Eh, well, my... I'm Stanley Goodspeed.
当然
But of course you are.
至少他名字没说错
Well, at least he got his name right.
我当然是
Of course I am. Huh.
你们有紧急状况
And you have an emergency.
是的
That's right.
你们需要我帮忙
And you need my help.
一点也没错
Exactly right.
-咖啡  -不用  我不喝  谢谢
-Coffee.  -No, no, I'm fine. Thank you.
给我喝咖啡
Offer me coffee.
是的  我正要问...
Oh, yes! Well, that was, in fact, gonna be my next...
来杯咖啡好吗?
Can we get a cup of coffee in here, please?
再解开这些东西  梅森先生  真的
And offer to take these off. Mr. Mason, really.
表示你们的诚意
As a gesture of your good faith.
犯人要求把手铐解开
Prisoner requests to have his handcuffs taken off.
请你们解开他的手铐
Why don't you go ahead and have his handcuffs taken off, please?
我想这也是个办法
Well, I guess that's one way to go.
这是司法部长的赦免令
This is a pardon and release contract from the Attorney General's office.
只要愿意合作  你就可重获自由
Now, it makes you a free man provided you cooperate.
如果你签名  就在上面写
So if you'll just, uh, sign...
签名的地方?
uh, at, uh, where it says..."Signature"?
没错
That's... Yes. "Signature."
拉丁文
Well, timeo danaos et dona ferentis.
我害怕希腊人  连他们送礼都得小心
"I fear the Greeks even when they bring gifts."
你很有学问!
Oh, an educated man!
看来你肯定不是实务探员
That rules out the possibility of you being a field agent.
老实说我是实务探员  梅森先生
In point of fact, I am a field agent, Mr. Mason.
-真的吗?  -没错
-Really?  -Yes.
是哪个领域的?
In which field?
反恐怖行动
Antiterrorism.
你是武器  爆破和搏击专家
Then you're trained in weaponry, explosives and mortal combat.
训练精良
Well-trained.
带我到费蒙饭店
Then it's the Fairmont Hotel.
好吧
Okay.
我要住套房  洗澡  刮胡子
I want a suite, a shower, a shave...
还有一套西装
and the feel of a suit.
我可以建议你剪个头发吗?
May I also suggest, uh, a haircut?
这样不流行吗?
Am I out of style?
除非你是西雅图来的二十岁吉他手
Unless you're a 20-year-old guitarist from Seattle.
那是邋遢型
It's a grunge thing.
邋遢型?
Grunge?
好吧  谢谢你
Yeah, well, uh, uh... Okay, thank you very much.
好了  联络费蒙饭店  必要时封闭楼层
All right. Call the Fairmont. Close the floor if necessary.
我要他与外界隔离
But I want him sealed off.
给他最多两个钟头时间
And he gets two hours max.
干得好  古斯比
Great job, Goodspeed.
何不请他到大溪地度假?
Why didn't you throw in a trip to Tahiti while you were at it?
我把这要交给司法部
I'll deliver this to the Attorney General.
不  把它给我
Uh, no, you'll give it to me. Give it to me, Reynolds.
把雷诺律师带出去  外面有车在等你  谢谢
And take Attorney Reynolds outside. There's a car waiting for you. Thank you.
那是已签署的联邦文件  那样做是违法的吧?
That's a signed federal document, sir. Isn't that illegal?
你并不清楚实际状况  古斯比
You're not acquainted with the full facts, Goodspeed.
我需要解释  长官  我对他有过承诺
With all due respect, sir, I'd like clarification. I gave that man my word.
该死!  这是最高机密  你没必要知道
Damn it! You're on a need-to-know basis, and you don't need to know.
我很好奇  但是
It's, uh, it's, eh, kind of curious, but, uh,
莱理爵士  阿格米达  索忍尼辛都受过冤狱
Sir Walter Raleigh, Alcamenes, Solzhenitsyn, they, um, well, they were all wrongfully imprisoned.
沃麦!  我就知道是你  你这混蛋!
Womack! Now, why am I not surprised, you piece of shit!
别动手!
Eh, peace! Peace!
没人在家  请留言
Hey, we're not home. Leave a message.
亲爱的  是我  听好
Hi, darling, it's, uh, it's me.
别来旧金山  我重复一次  千万别来旧金山
Uh, listen, don't come to San Francisco. I repeat, do not come to San Francisco.
史丹利  我一定要去的!
Stanley, no!
-卡拉  -我又不是没来过!
-Carla.  -Like hell I'm not coming!
等等  卡拉...
Wait. Car...
卡拉是谁?
Who's Carla?
你为什么不希望她来旧金山呢?
And why don't you want her to come to San Francisco?
这是最高机密  你没必要知道
You're on a need-to-know basis, and you don't need to know.
小心  他会咬人
Watch it, he'll bite you.
好
Good.
指挥中心一切就绪
Mobile Command is fully operational.
很好
Good. Mobile Command is fully operational.
我们两小时后到
We'll be there in approximately two hours.
我没有武器  长官
I'm not armed, sir.
我没有武器  长官?
I am unarmed, sir.
你的佩枪呢?
Well, where's your issue?
我放在袜柜里
I left it in my, uh, my sock drawer.
你要枪?
A gun?
要来干嘛  你只是个化学狂
For what? You're a chemical freak.
事实上我是个超级化学狂  但我还是需要一把枪
No, I'm a chemical super-freak, actually. But I still need a gun.
给他一把枪
Give him a goddamn gun.
毕业后你开过枪吗?
Have you fired one of those things since the Academy?
客房服务?
Uh, uh, room service?
这里是阁楼套房  你们有没有点心和饮料?
Ah, listen. This is the penthouse. Do you do snacks, drinks? Huh?
你好!
Hello!
-你是剃头师傅?  -不  叫我美发师
-You the barber?  -No. Stylist.
剃头师傅
Barber.
只准用推子  不准用剪刀
Just clippers. No scissors.
不准用剪刀?  你一定是在跟我开玩笑!
No scissors? You've got to be kidding me, no scissors!
你会叫毕加索  不准用画笔吗?
I mean, did they tell Picasso, "No brush"?
这个人能用剪刀杀人
With scissors, this man could kill you.
我用电动剪刀割不了任何人的鸟蛋吧?
I can't cut anyone's balls off with a trimmer now, can I?
咱们何不到阳台去晒点太阳
Why don't we do this outside? Get some sun.
谁帮你剪的头发  真是遭透了  逊毙了
Oh, who did this to you? This is just not right. In fact, it's nasty!
这是邋遢型
Well, it's a grunge thing.
的确很邋遢
Well, it's some kind of thing.
你想我们有没有时间能顺便护发和染发?
Do you think we have time for a sea kelp protein pack and maybe some color?
没有
No.
好吧
Okay.
他脾气很大  对不?
Not very nice, is he?
没错
No, he's not.
有人点的  别浪费食物
Hey, somebody ordered it. Can't let it go to waste.
你嘴巴停不下来吗?
Don't you ever stop eatin'?
食物免费的时候例外
Not when it's free.
我们在执勤
We're supposed to be on duty.
别担心  他只是个老头子
Hey, don't worry. He's an old man.
老板在看着他  来吃点龙虾
The boss is watchin' 'im. Come on. Have...Try some of this lobster.
我的秘书会跟你结帐
My secretary here will settle the bill.
办完事后你打算怎么处置我呢?  沃麦
So what do you have in store for me, Womack, when this is over?
你可以重获自由
You'll get your life back, Mason.
你早就可以让我重获自由
But you could've given me my life back years ago.
现在我为什么要相信你呢
Why should I trust you now?
我说话算话
You've got my word.
咱们握个手吧?
Will you shake on it?
别动  先生!
Freeze, mister!
救命啊
Help!
把枪放下  否则我就把你老大丢下去
Drop the gun, or I drop your boss.
你不会的!
You will not!
他越来越重了
He's getting very heavy.
把他拉上来
Then pull him up.
别这样!
Please don't!
救命啊!  妈的!
Help! Shit!
来块干贝吧  来  接着
Come on. Have a scallop. Come on. Catch.
你来拉他!
You hoist him!
来人!  来人!
Help! Help! Help!
梅森呢?
Where's Mason? Where is Mason?
抓紧
Help! Hang on!
梅森呢?
Where's Mason?
-他逃走了!  -逃了?
-Mason's gone!  -Gone?
客厅没人!
Living room's clear!
天啊!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
所有人员注意  紧急情况  他还在饭店里!
All units, this is Caretaker. We have a Signal Six. He's in the hotel!
我什么都不知道
Okay, I don't wanna know nothin'.
我根本没有看到你把那个人摔下阳台
I never saw you throw that gentleman off the balcony.
我只关心你对发型是否满意?
All I care about is, a-are you happy with your haircut?
轻点!
Easy!
轻点  蠢蛋  你快把我的手弄断了!
Watch it, you fuckhead, you're gonna pull my arm out!
这是我的宝贝车  千万别有任何损伤
This is my Humvee. I don't want any dings, dents or scratches, or I'll have your ass. Hey!
停住!
Hey! Stop! Hey!
联邦探员
FBI.
让开!
Move!
嫌犯开黑色军用车向西开去
Suspect is in a black Humvee, heading west on California.
时速约七十英里
Speed approximately 70 miles per hour.
快让开!
Get out of the way!
我要所有人员尽全力逮捕这个混蛋  听到了吗?
I want a net put on this son of a bitch, you hear me?
他想用这些东西挡住我们!
This guy's hittin' every fuckin' thing in sight tryin' to block us!
希望你们有保险!
I hope you're insured!
有何不可?
Oh, well, why not?
你跑不掉的!
You're goin' down!
我只是借你的车兜兜风
Hello? I'm only borrowing your Humvee!
查号台?  旧金山?
Information? San Francisco?
洁安琪萝  A  N  G
Uh, Jade Angelou. That's A-N-G...
欢迎  你们好吗?
Welcome aboard, y'all. How y'all doin' today?
稍等!
Hang on!
我的天啊!
Holy shit!
不!
Oh, no!
各自逃命吧!
We're gonna crash! Save yourselves!
我的宝贝!
Oh, my baby!
不!
Oh, no.
天啊!
Oh, God!
老兄  你撞烂了你的法拉利跑车
Hey, man, you just fucked up your Ferrari.
那不是我的
It's not mine.
这也不是!
Neither is this!
他妈的!  真该死!  那个混帐东西哪去了?
Damn! This sucks! Where's that son of a bitch at?
他死定了!  没人能救他!
I'm gonna hunt him down! That motherfucker ain't safe nowhere.
化学武器部门
Chem weapons. Isherwood.
马文!
Marvin!
查一查渥堡联邦监狱
Look up Wolfburg Federal Penitentiary.
囚犯姓名是约翰·梅森
The inmate is Mason, John.
史坦利  听着  我不吃这狗屁公家饭了
Hey, Stan, listen, I'm gettin' out of this government shithole.
我要去设计捕蟑螂器  棒吧?
I'm goin' over to Orkin to design roach motels. Cool, huh?
我刚抢了一个孩子的机车
Look, I just stole a kid's motorcycle.
我感觉很不好
I'm not really feeling too good about it, okay?
快查渥堡联邦监狱
Wolfburg. Got it?
马格尔  梅斯尼  没有梅森
Yeah, I got it. All right, Magrane, Masconi, Masters. No Mason.
查查一九七六年二月
Go to February '76.
那时有谁从圣昆丁监狱移监去渥堡?
Who was transferred to Wolfburg from San Quentin?
这真奇怪
This is weird. They got medical records.
有病历  出生地在苏格兰
They got place of birth. Glasgow.
但是没有名字
Uh, but they don't have a name.
等等  有家属资料
Uh, wait a minute, wait a minute. They have next of kin.
旧金山史顿大道32号的  洁安琪萝
A Jade Angelou of 32 Stenson Drive, San Francisco.
洁?
Jade?
我是史黛西  是洁的朋友
No, Stacy. Jade's friend.
你不敢一个人来?
Were you afraid to come alone?
没错
Yeah.
没关系
It's okay.
如果有需要我就在那儿
I'll be over here if you need me.
上回看到照片你才十岁
The last photograph I had of you, you were about ten.
母亲去世后?
Yeah?
我找到你的照片
Well, I found a picture of you among my mom's things when she died.
你想走走吗?
Oh, yeah? Well, uh... Why don't we take a walk?
我找到他了  他在艺术殿
I got 'im. Palace of Fine Arts.
你母亲她很特别
Your mother, uh... Yeah, well, sh-she was very special.
是的  没错
Yeah, she was.
但别把你和她之间的事想得太浪漫了
But I don't think that we should romanticize what happened between you and her.
在齐柏林合唱团演唱会后在酒吧搭上
Meeting in a bar after a Led Zeppelin concert.
结果我就出生了
Head out, and I was the result.
我们本来会有好结果  只可惜...
Well, I'd like to think it would've led somewhere if only...
只可惜什么?  可惜你...
If only what? Six federal marshals hadn't kicked down our door...
硬是被警察逮回大牢去了?
and dragged you back to prison?
-对不起  -没关系
-I'm sorry.  -It's all right.
你被放出来了?
So, they let you out?
是的
Yeah.
很好
That's good.
你到底犯了什么罪?
What did you do?
洁  我的时间不多
Jade, I don't have a great deal of time here.
但我会回来找你的...
But I'll be coming back. And, uh...
也许我们可以...
Maybe we can...
怎样?  我们可以怎样?
What? We can what?
你知道吗?  只有你能证明...我存在
You know, you're almost the only evidence...that I exist.
但我不了解你
But I don't know you.
那是可以改变的
That's what I want to change, eh?
我不断地练习见到你该说些什么
I've rehearsed this speech a thousand times on the chance that we would meet.
我们见面了  我却语塞了
Here we are, and I'm lost.
我也不知道该怎么想
Well, I don't know how I'm supposed to be feeling either.
洁  我不是坏人
Jade, I'm not an evil man.
你若相信  那就是好的开始
If you can believe that, then it's a start.
好吧
Okay.
他们是来找你的?
Is this about you?
你又逃狱了  对吧?
You broke out of prison again, didn't you?
你为何来找我呢?
Why did you come to me?
联邦探员  小姐  令尊为我们工作
FBI, ma'am. Your father's working with us.
他正在帮忙我们解决致命的危机
He's helping us resolve a dangerous situation.
-真的?  -没错  小姐
-He is?  -Yes, ma'am.
约翰  我想我们该走了吧?
Well, gee whiz, John, I guess we oughta get goin', huh?
随你吩咐  史丹利
Whatever you say, Stanley.
谢谢你  你大可不必那样做的
Thank you for that. You could've handled it differently.
我们废话少说吧  混球
What do you say we cut the chitchat, a-hole?
差点害死我两次  我的下巴痛死了!
You almost got me killed twice. And my jaw hurts like hell!
很好
Good.
卑鄙的傢伙!
Cocksucker!
我应该把你送回大牢...
If I had my way, you would be shipped back to Wolfburg in leg irons...
让你的余生不见天日!
and caged like an animal for the rest of your natural fucking life!
你毁了半个旧金山!
You wrecked half the city!
请你说明地下隧道
Now, tell me about the tunnels.
只要摸熟整个系统  你哪儿都能去
If you know the system, it will take you wherever you need to go.
这里有个水管入口  它低于水面
All right, there's an intake pipe here, below low tide.
那是我们最佳的入口吗?
Is that our best access?
对  我就是从这儿逃出
Yes. That's exactly where I had come out.
贮水池底下连结着  污水处理系统
Then beneath the cistern, there's a connection to the abandoned septic system.
贮水池底下连结着污水处理系统
那有多长?
How many feet is that?
57步
Uh, 57 paces.
然后要怎么走?
Where do we go from there?
问得好
That's a good question.
我不晓得
I have no idea.
什么?
What?
我是说  进去了我才知道
I mean, I'll know it when we're all inside.
你不能去  用蓝图跟我们解释
No. You're not goddamn goin'. Show us on the blueprints.
不行  我的蓝图在我脑里
I can't! My blueprint was in my head.
我曾经在黑暗中潜伏在地底三天...
I was underground for three days in the dark...
指示等待正确的潮汐到来
just waiting for the tides to be right.
别担心  我会记起来的
But don't worry. It'll all come back to me.
你哪儿都别想去  梅森
You're not going anywhere, Mason.
等等  他可能是他们唯一的希望
Wait a second. Now, this piece of work might be the only chance those people over there have.
如果他不去  那我们放他出来干嘛?
If he's not going, then why the hell did we get him out of jail?
-他很聪明  -他只能指路  不能跟去
-He's smart.  -I got him out to get you people in, not go with you.
如果他是唯一清楚的人  他就得去了
If it's the only way of getting the intelligence I need, then he goes.
他会害你们
He'll fuck with you.
你若敢害我兄弟  我会让你死的很惨
You compromise my men's lives, and I'll bury you out there.
沃麦...
Now, Womack...
我看你别无选择了
you're between The Rock and a hard case.
你的手没事吧?
How is your bowling arm?
古斯比博士  目标是要摧毁发射架
Dr. Goodspeed, the goal is to take out the launchers,
并且拆除VX毒气弹
then neutralize the V.X. Chemical rounds.
我们从卫星感热图看到导弹在停尸间...
Well, we know the poison's being kept in the prison morgue from the satellite thermal imaging...
就是这里  颜色变深的地方
which is right here; these colorized dots.
你看过真正的毒气导弹吗?
Have you ever actually seen one of these devices?
不  我只研究过
No, sir, but I've studied them.
我该开始教你们如何拆除引信并解毒了
I should really begin briefing your guys on defusing and detoxification.
这里有张图  是毒胶囊和导弹的结构详图
Got a really neat layout over here of the chem round as well as the rocket...
我们开始吧
So let's get rolling.
没有必要
That won't be necessary.
非常有必要
Oh, it's very necessary, sir.
这种毒气的杀伤力惊人
The power of this chemical is way beyond anything you can imagine.
会造成生态浩劫的
An ecological disaster, sir.
再加上它的设计相当复杂
Plus the devices themselves are complicated.
所以你得跟来
That's why you're coming with us.
-是吗?  -你是专家  有问题吗?
-I am?  -You're the expert. What's your problem?
我得跟去?  一起潜到水底?
You mean I'm going, going out there, under the water?
你今天早上不是要枪吗?
Well, earlier today you wanted a gun.
你现在有枪和潜水衣了
Now you're getting a gun and a wet suit.
你参加过战斗吗?
Have you ever been in a combat situation?
请解释战斗的定义  先生
Define "combat," sir.
薜普?
Shep?
袭击在坚固碉堡内的海陆精英...
An incursion underwater to retake an impregnable fortress held by an elite team...
救出人质  夺回十五枚...
of U.S. Marines in possession of 81 hostages and 15 guided rockets...
毒气导弹
armed with V.X. Poisoned gas.
这么说来我没有参加过  失陪一下
Oh. In that case, no, sir. Excuse me.
-给  -谢谢
-Here.  -Ah, thank you.
你脸色不太好
You don't look too good.
事实上简直是糟透了
In fact, you look like shit.
我的肚子在天翻地复
My stomach's doing hula hoops around my ass.
你没事吧?
You all right?
我是说  你办得到吗?
I mean, you gonna make it through this thing?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道一定会面对这种事...
I always expected something like this was going to happen...
怎么准备都没用的
but nothing prepares you for it.
现在整个城市的命运...
Now I'm... I'm responsible...
都系在我的手中
for a whole city.
我知道这对你而言并不简单
Look, I know this isn't easy for you.
你受过这方面的训练...
Remember, you were trained for this kind of a situation...
相信我  你会想起来的
and believe me, it'll come back to you.
更何况还有全国最顶尖的特遣队协助你
Besides, you got the best SEAL team in the country backing you up.
好吧  你说得对
Okay. You're right.
我会在无线电上指点你
I-I'll be on the wire. I'll help talk you through it.
还有一件事
There's something else.
很糟糕  不  很美好
It's terrible. N-No, it's wonderful...
现在却很糟糕
except it isn't.
我女友怀孕了...
My girlfriend's pregnant...
她正飞来旧金山看我
and she's just flown in to see me.
你今晚尽管专心完成任务
You keep your mind on what you're going to be doing out there tonight.
我会派人把你女友接到指挥中心来的
And I'll send someone to pick up your girlfriend and bring her here to the command center.
汉默!
Hummel!
你好  法兰克  我是林斯壮
Hello, Frank. Lou Linstrom.
克拉玛将军和我在白宫
I'm at the White House with General Kramer.
法兰克  我们在转帐时出了点问题
Uh, Frank, uh, we're havin' a few problems with the account transfer.
别啰唆  我要解决方法
Don't tell me problems. Tell me solutions.
我们跟总统谈过...
Now, we've spoken to the president...
你知道总统对恐怖行动的立场
and I know that you're well aware of his stance on terrorism.
-所以我们打算...  -这不是恐怖行动  这是正义
-So what we'd like to do is...  -This isn't about terrorism. This is about justice.
也是要提醒那些为政治理由遗弃他人的家伙
It's about reminding you people who found it politically convenient to forget.
这样说是没用的  法兰克
This is goin' nowhere, Frank.
让我告诉你吧
Well, then, let me tell you what is.
十五枚毒气弹将会击中旧金山市中心
Fifteen V.X. Gas rockets into the heart of San Francisco.
我给你十七小时去弄钱
You've got 17 hours to deliver the money.
否则后果将不堪设想  各位
Or be prepared to reap the whirlwind, gentlemen.
铝热剂好了吗?
What's the word from Mojave?
彼得森将军说不保证...
General Peterson can give us...
能起作用
no definite assurance on the thermite plasma.
就这样了
That is the word.
派特遣队进攻
Green light to SEAL incursion.
距离时限十五小时
集合!  好了  大伙听好
Fall in! All right, listen up.
梅森先生带头
Mr. Mason will run point for us.
薜普紧跟着他
Lieutenant Shepard will be attached to his hip.
你呼吸  他跟你一起  你想小便  他会帮忙
You breathe, he breathes with you. You piss, he helps.
懂了吗?
Understood?
古斯博士是位专家
Dr. Goodspeed is our specialist.
当他解除毒气导弹后  我们就发射绿色信号弹并等待救援
When he neutralizes the threat, we launch green flares and we wait for the cavalry.
别怀疑各位  这是最艰巨的一战...
Make no mistake, gentlemen. We're in the fight of our lives...
对手是越战中最伟大的指挥官  我没有唬你们
against maybe the greatest battalion commander in the Vietnam War. I shit you not.
有问题吗?
Any questions?
出发!
Let's load up!
你先请  高手
After you, ace.
戴上迷你摄影机
Pass out and activate the minicams.
一切就绪了吗?  摄影机启动了吗?
Everything set here? Minicams operational?
启动了长官  正在传讯中
Roger that, sir. We are on-line.
薜普  梅森先生有何装备?
Shep, what's the status on the special operational gear for Mr. Mason?
我看看  喷筒里装有一夸特燃油
Uh, let's see. We have, uh...one quart of kerosene in a squeeze bottle.
三个橡皮垫圈和防水火柴
Three washers and waterproof matches.
这是拆除导弹后要发射的绿色信号弹
Use the green flares to signal when the threat has been neutralized.
这是颠茄素  一但接触到毒气...
Now, this is atropine. If you come in contact with the gas...
在二十秒内注射进心脏
you have 20 seconds to inject it into your heart.
别迟疑  这能救命
Don't fuck with me on this. It may save your life.
锁定三架飞行物向此飞来  方位275
I have three incoming bogeys bearing 275.
距离  六千英尺
Range: 6,000 meters.
FBI指挥中心?
FBI Command Center?
你们可不可以告诉我  发生什么事了?
Oh, I would just love for you to tell me what is goin' on.
不行
Nope.
听着  史丹利·古斯比是我的男朋友
Listen, Stanley Goodspeed is my boyfriend.
实际上他是我的未婚夫
Actually, he's, um, my fiance.
-他人呢?  -这是机密  小姐
-Where is he?  -Classified, lady.
好吧你就像个白痴坐在这里吧
Okay. Well, you just sit here and act like a Bureau bonehead, then.
你上哪儿?  可恶!
Hey, where are you g... Goddamn it!
诱导直升机飞向恶魔岛
Decoy choppers commencing run to Alcatraz.
失去一架的踪影  我失去一架的踪迹
I just lost one, sir. I just lost one.
两架正飞来  一架失去踪影
-We only got two flying in. I just lost one.
可恶!
Shit!
以前我们只靠面罩和蛙鞋
In my day, we did it all with a snorkel and a pair of flippers.
以前?
Your day?
你不知道我的资历?
Yes. Didn't you read my resume?
我对你一无所知
I don't... I don't know anything about you.
我对你略有所知  古人
Hmm. I know something about you, Godspell.
古斯比
Goodspeed.
古斯比  古人  古董...
Goodspeed, Godspeed, Godspell...
你没受过反恐训练
you never went to any antiterrorist school.
你可千万别害我们送命了
So just make sure you don't get us all fucking killed.
我们要下降了
We're goin' dark.
夜视镜!
Night vision!
突击一号正在金银岛附近...
Raider One has dropped below radar coverage...
低飞躲避雷达侦测
heading around Treasure Island.
长官  有两架飞行物  正从东方接近中
Sir, we've got two bogeys bearing due east and closing.
诱饵吗?
Decoys?
准备出发!
Prepare to deploy!
祝好运  队长
Good luck, Commander.
突击一号到达目标区
Sir, Raider One is at the drop zone.
史丹利不太会游泳  更别说是潜水了
Stanley's not a very good swimmer. I mean, he can't even snorkel.
大家准备好了吗?
Everyone, good to go?
准备完毕!
Good to go!
-准备完毕!  -准备完毕!
-Good to go!  -Good to go! Good to go!
出发  队员潜入水中
All right, so the S.D.U. S have been deployed, and the Eagles are in the water.
少校  我要有人去巡逻西区
Major, I want the perimeter patrolled to the west end of the island.
-轮流巡视  -是长官  韩德!
-Double-time it.  -Yes, sir. Hendrix!
-你带队  -遵命
-You lead the patrol.  -Aye, aye, sir.
快点!  快点!
Let's move. Move out! Move out! Move out!
队员进入恶魔岛
The Eagles are on The Rock.
他们进入贮水池了
They've entered the cistern room.
真是多谢了  梅森
Thank you very fucking much, Mr. Mason.
这地方根本没有出口
You've led us into a room with no exit.
有办法吗?
Any ideas, Dillinger?
快点想  咱们现在是坐以待毙
Figure it out soon. We're sitting ducks.
我们时间不多
We're a little tight on time.
你们在门边等着  等我把门打开
You stand by the door until I open it.
我想知道你打算怎么开门呢?
I'd like to know how you plan on accomplishing that?
从这儿去
Through here.
你唬我
You're shitting me.
我还记得时间差
I memorized the timing.
希望没有改变
I just hope it hasn't been changed.
你要是被喷到你就成木炭了
You catch one of those flame bursts, you're a corpse.
谢谢
Thank you.
队长你叫我紧跟着他的...
Commander, you said never to leave his sight, but, uh...
留下来
Stand fast, Lieutenant.
祝你们愉快
Have a nice day.
你们哪儿找来这傢伙的?
Where'd you dig up this guy?
那是机密
That's classified.
这里没人长官  感应器也没有感应
Clear here, sir. No motion sensors tripped.
没有动静
Nothing.
叫他们继续巡逻
Well, tell 'em to stay out there.
向前搜索!
Sweep forward!
看来他撇下我们了
Looks like he fucked us, Commander.
我就知道  那傢伙开溜了
I knew it. That son of a bitch jumped ship.
欢迎光临恶魔岛
Welcome to The Rock.
-梅森  -不对
-Mason.  -That's a no-no.
那是地下道
That's the subway.
那里才能进入隧道
That'll drop you into the tunnels.
动手!
Do it!
长官  队员进入地下隧道
Sir, the Eagles have breached the tunnel system.
你很愉快吗?
You enjoying this?
至少比牢里好多了
Well, it's certainly more enjoyable than my average day.
读读哲学  在厕所还得小心有人会强暴我
Reading philosophy, avoiding gang rape in the washroom.
最近情况好多了
Though it's less of a problem these days.
我人老珠黄了  也许没有吸引力了
Maybe I'm losing my sex appeal.
北边的防风栅栏有震动
We've got seismic activity in one of the storm grates. North side.
继续巡逻该区
Continue patrolling the area.
向前搜索!
Sweep forward!
慢着  有动静
Commander, halt. We've got movement.
上头有声音
They're hearing sounds above, sir.
别动
Stand fast.
趴下  趴下
Down, down, down.
西边防风栅栏安全
West storm drain's clear.
离淋浴室只有97步
Ninety-seven paces to the shower room.
队员抵达隧道入口  就在淋浴室底下
The Eagles are now at the access tunnel. They're right under the shower room, sir.
光纤摄影机
Fiber optics.
有点不对
Something's not right.
我有不好的预感
I got a bad feeling about this.
安静
Quiet.
动作感应器
Motion sensors.
雷射光横射过铁盖
Beams cutting across the manhole covers.
搞定它
Deal with it.
雷射光可能反射在棱镜上
Commander, the beam is hitting some sort of reflective device. Possibly a prism.
我要用镜子...
I want to use a mirror to cut the beam...
把雷射光折射回原点
send the beam back to its source.
然后我就移开棱镜
And then I'm gonna move the prism.
淋浴室的震动感应器有动静  长官
We've got motion on a trembler in the shower room, sir.
我们有客人了
We've got visitors.
走吧
Let's move.
好了  可以出去
Got it. Good to go.
-妈的!  我就知道!  -快点!
-Fuck, man! I knew this would happen! Fuck!  -Move!
留下来  我们先清场
Stand fast. We'll secure the area.
他们进入淋浴室了  长官
They're entering into the shower room, sir.
他们正在清场
They're securing the area.
别乱动
Just sit tight.
放下武器!
Drop your weapons! Drop 'em!
放下武器!  快点
Stand fast!
别开枪!
Hold your fire!
放下武器!
Drop your weapons!
别开枪!
Hold your fire!
这是个陷阱
It's a fucking trap.
我是汉默准将
This is General Hummel.
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
放下!
Drop 'em!
我是安德逊中校  汉默将军
Anderson here, General Hummel.
特遣队队长
Commander. Team leader.
安德逊中校  如果你爱惜兄弟性命
Commander Anderson, if you have any concern for the lives of your men...
你就命令他们放下武器
you will order them to safety their weapons and place them on the deck.
糟了
This is not happening.
我们知道你的目的
Sir, we know why you're out here.
我也完全同意你
God knows I agree with you.
但我也跟你一样立誓捍卫祖国抵挡敌人...
But like you, I swore to defend this country against all enemies...
不论他们是外国人或是本国人
foreign, sir, and domestic.
将军  我们都为这国家洒下热血
General, we've spilled the same blood in the same mud.
你知道我不能下达这个命令
You know goddamn well I can't give that order.
我们死定了
We're dead.
我们居高临下  中校
Your unit is covered from an elevated position, Commander.
我不会再要求你了  别做傻事
I'm not gonna ask you again. Don't do anything stupid.
没有人需要死在这里
No one has to die here.
你们这些人  你们在海军陆战队誓言效忠国家!
Men following the general, you're under oath as United States Marines!
你们忘了吗?
Have you forgotten that?
我们都有袍泽丧命战场
We all have shipmates we remember.
有些甚至是被五角大厦的人所遗弃
Some of them were shit on and pissed on by the Pentagon.
但你们也无权叛变啊!
But that doesn't give you the right to mutiny!
随你怎么说  我们占了优势
You call it what you want!
你们犯了大错  中校
You're down there, we're up here. You walked into the wrong goddamn room, Commander!
-别动!  -该死  中校  最后一次
-Stand fast!  -Goddamn it, Commander, one last time.
命令你的手下放下武器
You tell your men to safety their weapons, drop 'em on the deck.
-我无法下达那个命令!  -我不想再说一次
-I cannot give that order!  -I am not gonna repeat that order!
-我无法下达那个命令  -你是怎么了?
-I will not give that order!  -What the hell is wrong with you, man?
-别动!  -别动!
-Stand fast!  -Oh, my God!
-我再说一次-我们干掉他们吧...
-Let's waste these fuckers.  -One last time. You order your men to safety their weapons...
停火!
Cease fire!
别去
Don't go.
停火!
Cease fire!
该死!  可恶!
Shit! Goddamn it!
放开我  放开我!
Let go of me. Let go of me!
别去
Don't. Don't go.
完了
It's over.
天啊!
Oh, God!
-还有动静  -谁?
-We got some movement.  -Who?
两个人!
Two of 'em!
是谁?
Who is it?
11  12号
Eagles 11 and 12.
古斯比和梅森
L-lt's Goodspeed and Mason.
我就知道
I knew it.
我们得尽快组成第二队  再次行动
I've gotta get a team together right now. We've gotta move with the second option.
让他们再被屠杀?  不行
What, and invite another massacre? No way.
只剩一只老狐狸和菜鸟  我告诉你  没戏唱了
We've got a 60-year-old convict and a lab rat. I'm telling you, it's over.
梅森还没玩完  不是吗?
Not for Mason, it isn't.
古斯比  我不会杀你的
Goodspeed, I'm not gonna kill you.
你上哪儿?
Where are you going?
离开此地
Off this bloody island.
为什么?
What? Wh-Wh-What for?
古斯比?  古斯比  你收到吗?
Goodspeed. Goodspeed, do you read me?
找你的
It's for you.
长官?
Sir?
情况如何?
What's the status?
他们死了  全死了!
The status is they're dead. They're dead!
只剩我和梅森  梅森正要走
It's just me and Mason. Now he says he's leaving.
不行  听到吗?  不行!
That is unacceptable. Do you hear me? Unacceptable!
有点麻烦  长官  他手上有枪
Well, there's a problem, sir. He's got a gun.
你只有水枪吗?
What do you have, a fuckin' water pistol?
不是
No, sir.
去阻止他
Go after him and stop him.
我不想这样
I didn't want this.
天啊  我并不想这样
Jesus, I didn't want this.
这是无可避免的  法兰克
You knew this might happen, Frank.
-也许他们会付钱给我们  -也许不会
-Well, maybe now they'll pay up.  -Maybe now they won't, Captain.
也许我们该处决一些人质
Then maybe we need to execute a few hostages.
有一个活口!
Got a live one!
打死他
Put a bullet in him.
你听到了  解决他!
You heard him. End it!
收起手枪
Holster that sidearm, Captain.
长官?
Sir?
你犯了大错
You made a terrible mistake.
害他们白白牺牲
And more of our brothers have died in vain.
是你们逼我的
Damn you for forcing me into this position.
我现在就要单独跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you right now, alone.
你说这是最高机密
Now you told me I'm on a need-to-know basis.
我现在告诉你
And I'm tellin' you right now.
我要知道约翰·梅森的身份  长官
I need to know who the fuck John Mason is right now, sir.
你真的想知道?
All right, you wanna know?
一九六二年  胡佛...
1962, J. Edgar Hoover...
掌管调查局
is head of the FBI.
有人说他控管了整个国家
Some say the country.
他秘密调查美国和欧洲的政要
It's no secret he kept microfilm files on prominent Americans and Europeans:
戴高乐  英国议员和首相
De Gaulle, British members of Parliament, even the prime minister.
他有每个人的秘密档案
I mean, this guy had dirt on everybody in the world.
我听过传闻  这和梅森又有何关系?
Yeah, I know all the cloak-and-dagger stories. Where does Mason fit in?
他就是偷走档案的英国间谍
Mason was the British operative who stole the files.
但我们在加拿大边界逮到他
But our Bureau agents caught him at the Canadian border.
当然英国不承认他的身份
Of course, the British claimed they'd never heard of him.
我们将他囚禁...
And we held him without trial...
逼他交出胶片
until he gave up the microfilm.
但是他没有交出来
But he never did.
真令人讶异  胡佛没用他女儿逼他
Well, I'm surprised Hoover didn't use his daughter as leverage.
胡佛于一九七二年去世  那时她还没出世
Hoover was dead in '72. She wasn't born yet.
现在的调查局不同了
Today, well, it's a different Bureau.
他被关了一辈子!  没有任何公平的审判
So you held this guy without trial his whole life!
也难怪他会生气
No wonder he's pissed.
他知道美国半个世纪以来埋藏最深的秘密
This man knows our most intimate secrets from the last half century:
外星人登陆  刺杀肯尼迪的真凶
The alien landing at Roswell, the truth about the J.F.K. Assassination.
梅森很生气  梅森很危险  他是个职业杀手
And Mason's angry, he's lethal, he's a trained killer.
而他也是我们手上唯一的希望
And he is the only hope that we have got.
梅森!  梅森!
Mason! Mason!
上面有81名人质
There are 81 hostages still up there.
是啊  我也是人质
Yeah, like me.
你想来硬的?
All right, you wanna play tough?
你想跟我来硬的?
You wanna play tough with me?
好  FBI!
Okay. FBI!
别动  浑蛋!
Freeze, sucker!
我会开枪的
I'll fire.
不  你不会
No, you won't.
放下枪
Throw down.
你不是那种人
You're not the sort.
我们等着瞧吧
Let's find out.
我是  你不是
I could; you, no.
而且你保险没开
Besides, your safety's on.
古斯比  你的情况解决了吗?
Goodspeed, have you resolved the situation?
还没有
Not yet.
-现在枪都在他手上了  -该死!
-He's got all the guns now, sir.  -Shit!
没错  我不用枪  我也不会踹门
You're right, I don't use guns and I don't kick down doors.
这才是我在做的事
This is what I do.
我没戴眼镜
I haven't got my glasses.
上面写  化学武器专家
What it says is Chemical Weapons Specialist.
没错
That's right. I got a lunatic up there, man...
上面那疯子有十五枚致命的毒气导弹
with 15 missiles armed with some really funky stuff.
沃麦这大骗子  你可以警告我女儿的
That lying Womack. You could've told my daughter.
那是机密  我也面临相同的状况
It was classified. Look, I'm in the same situation.
我怀孕的女友也在旧金山
They've got my girlfriend in the city with a baby on the way.
我能拆除导弹  我真的可以
Look, I can defuse the rockets. I really can.
不过我需要你的帮忙  就现在
But I'm gonna need your help, and I'm gonna need it right now.
长官  他的武器和通话机不见了!
Sir, this man's weapons and tack radio are missing!
该死  有鼠辈横行  把他们揪出来
Shit, we got a rodent problem. Flush the pipes.
底下的隧道像迷宫  仔细搜
There's probably a maze of tunnels on this goddamn island. Check every access you can find.
就算你逃出恶魔岛...也躲不过导弹的
Even if you escape from the island...you can't escape the rockets.
你打算逃到哪儿?
So, where are you gonna go?
去哪?  做什么?
Go where? What are, what are you gonna do?
告诉我停尸间在哪儿  梅森
Show me where the morgue is, Mason.
我要出去了
I'm out of here.
你不管你的女儿吗?  梅森?
What about your daughter? Mason?
找到了
Rodents located.
我看你别无选择  对吧?
The way I see it, you don't really have any choice, do you?
我不认为你有
I don't think you do.
快跑!
Move!
他们盯上我们了
They're onto us.
用火把他们烧出来
Burn 'em out.
这玩意可厉害了
This mother's gonna blow big.
我不了解  怎么会突然失去通讯?
I don't understand. How could we lose radio contact all of a sudden?
我们失去通讯了  但雷达还有显示
We've lost coms. Still got 'em on locaters.
你怎么说?
So what's it gonna be?
什么?
What?
你有别的选择吗?
How do you like your choices?
没有
I don't.
所以说
That's what I thought.
来吧
All right, come on.
这是恶魔岛最古老的地方
This is the oldest part of Alcatraz.
这原来是美国内战的碉堡
Did you know it was originally a Civil War fort?
真的吗?
Oh, really?
你知道吗  我也喜欢历史...
Huh. Yeah, wow. You know, I like history, too...
也许这一切结束后  咱们再来研究
and maybe when this is all over, you and I can stop by the souvenir shop together.
不过现在我只想...找到导弹
But right now I just... I just... I wanna find some rockets.
别惹火我  我们正要去停尸间
Don't tempt me. We are going to the morgue.
你可以吗?
You sure you're ready for this?
我会尽力而为
I'll do my best.
尽力而为?
Your best?
输家总是抱怨他们已经尽力了
Losers always whine about their best.
赢家才能搞上选美皇后
Winners go home and fuck the prom queen.
卡拉是选美皇后
Carla was the prom queen.
真的吗?
Really?
真的
Yeah.
雷达显示他们接近停尸间
Locaters have them approaching the morgue, sir.
加油  你办得到的
Come on, come on. You can do it, Doc.
千万别迟疑
You must never hesitate.
你差点射到导弹
I think you're shooting too close to the rocket.
别射到导弹
Him, but not the rocket.
还有什么吩咐吗教授?
Any other news, Professor?
别射到导弹!
Not the rocket!
别射到导弹
Not the rocket.
我要让你们好看
I got a little somethin' for ya.
这是我见过死的最惨的人
Oh, yeah, okay. That's just about the most awful thing I've ever seen.
梅森...
Mason...
一不小心  你就会送命
the second you don't respect this, it kills you.
放过去
Put it over there.
你看过尸体  那样算是正常的吗?
You've been around a lot of corpses. Is that normal?
-脚在抖?  -对  就是脚在抖
-What, the feet thing?  -Yeah, the feet thing.
那很正常
Yeah, that happens.
那让我集中不了精神
Well, I'm having kind of a hard time concentrating.
你能想点办法吗?
Can you do something about it?
要怎样?  再杀死他一次吗?
Well, like what? Kill him again?
听着  我只是个生化专家
Listen, I'm just a biochemist.
成天关在实验室  生活平淡
And most of the time I work in a glass jar and lead a very uneventful life.
开着棕色的富豪车  不过我现在要处理的是...
I drive a Volvo, a beige one. But what I'm dealing with here...
这世上最致命的物质
is one of the most deadly substances the Earth has ever known.
所以拜托你别惹我
So what do you say you cut me some friggin' slack?
一串串相当晶莹剔透
A really elegant string-of-pearls configuration.
但不幸的是它们非常不稳定
Unfortunately, incredibly unstable.
这东西能有什么作用?
Well, what exactly does this stuff do?
导弹将之汽化后能够杀死一整个城市的居民
If the rocket renders it aerosol, it can take out the entire city of people.
真的吗?
Really?
如果你掉下一个呢?
And what happens if you drop one?
很幸运地只会杀死我们俩
Happily, it'll just wipe out you and me.
怎么杀?
How?
它会在三十秒之内...
It's a cholinesterase inhibitor...
切断大脑至脊椎的神经信息
Stops the brain from sending nerve messages down the spinal cord within 30 seconds.
如果你暴露在它之下  你就会懂了
Any epidermal exposure or inhalation, and you'll know.
毒药侵袭神经系统  导致后背部剧痛
A twinge at the small of your back as the poison seizes your nervous system.
别动它!
Do not move that!
你的肌肉收缩  呼吸困难
Your muscles freeze, you can't breathe.
强烈的痉挛能让你的五腑内脏翻出来
You spasm so hard you break your own back, spit your guts out.
不过皮肤会先融化
But that's after your skin melts off.
我的天啊
My God.
我想老天是站在我们这边的  对吧?
Oh, I think we'd like God on our side at the moment, don't you?
我现在要把导航晶片拆掉...
So what I'm doing now is removing the guidance system chips...
导弹在五百尺后会落海
so the rocket will splash down after 500 feet.
给我
All right, let me have that.
你可以放手
You can let go of it.
退后  退后!
All right, just back away. Just back away!
长官  停尸间小队没有回音
Sir, morgue team has not checked in.
黑鸟一号  这是黑鸟  请回答
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird. Over.
黑鸟一号  这是黑鸟  请回答  该死的!
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird. Come in, goddamn it!
还有敌人  快去!
Somebody's still there. Let's move!
还有鼠辈!  封锁停尸间  封锁停尸间
Rats alive! Close on the morgue. Close on the morgue.
快  快  快
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
动作快点  我们还有敌人!
Frye, Darrow, hustle up. We got more company!
到停尸间会合  快去
Converge on the morgue. Move out.
古斯比  快点过来
Goodspeed, come on. Come over here.
我最爱压力了  那是我每天的家常便饭
Good. I love pressure. I eat it for breakfast.
快点  来不及了
Come on. Time's up.
还有三枚导弹在别的地方  我们一定要找到它们
There's three rockets somewhere else. We have to find them.
快点!
Come on!
我玩这个太老了
I'm too old for this.
现在去哪儿?
Where's it go?
我不晓得
I've no idea.
长官  所有的导航晶片都不见了
Sir, all the guidance chips are gone.
你没除掉鼠辈
Captain, I guess you didn't quite take care of the rat problem.
是的  长官
No, sir.
这里死了两个人...
Well, there are two dead men here...
我建议你最好把他们解决掉
who strongly suggest you go finish the job.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
是  长官!  瑞欧  罗斯  来吧!
Yes, sir! Rio, Royce, let's go!
快!
Move out!
你不知道通往哪儿?
You really don't know where this goes?
没错  我不知道
No, I don't know where it goes.
我们越来越快了  你知道怎么让它慢下来吗?
Well, it's starting to pick up speed. Do you know how to slow it down?
不  我不知道
No, I don't.
上帝啊
God.
梅森  你还好吧?
Mason, you all right?
好得很  你这个大白痴!
Yes, perfectly okay, you fucking idiot!
他们追来了
They're coming.
谁?
Who?
海军陆战队!
The marines!
哪里?
Where?
怎么回事?
What the fuck's goin' on?
把他拦住
Let's cut him off.
梅森!
Mason!
你这混蛋!  去死吧!
You motherfucker! Die! Die! Die!
我很高兴你没有考虑太久
I'm rather glad you didn't hesitate too long.
你怎么能保持冷静?
How do you do it?
我受过世界顶尖的英国情报局严格训练
Oh, I was trained by the best. British Intelligence.
来吧
Come on.
老实说我情愿当诗人或农夫
But in retrospect, I'd rather have been a poet or a farmer.
距离时限八小时
总统三小时后到
Okay, the president arrives in three hours.
能拖多久就拖多久  然后进行空袭
His directive is to string Hummel along until the air strike is operational.
铝热剂进展如何?
What's the word from Mohave, General?
还是一样
The same as last time, Lou.
他们还在赶工
They're going as fast as they can.
跪下来!
On your knees. On your knees!
特遣队员  你手上有我的东西
Navy SEALs, listen up. You've got something that belongs to me.
正确的说是十二片导航晶片
Twelve guidance chips, to be precise.
让我提醒你们  我手上有危在旦夕的人质
Let me remind you there are lives at stake, civilian lives.
说话
Speak up.
说话!
Speak up!
告诉他们你的名字
Tell them your name.
我叫赖瑞韩德逊
My name is Larry Henderson.
-糟糕  -我有三个孩子
-Oh, man.  -And I'm a father of three.
他拿枪指着我的脑袋
And, uh, they've got a gun to my head.
你们有三分钟可以交出导航晶片...
You've got exactly three minutes to return the guidance chips to the exercise yard...
否则韩德逊先生就没命了
or Mr. Henderson won't have a head.
不
Oh, no.
还有三枚导弹  找到并且拆除它们  好吗?
Now, three to go. You find them and defuse them, okay?
-好的  -很好
-All right.  -All right.
我去找汉默  试着帮你拖延一些时间
I'll try and delay Hummel and give you more time.
那韩德逊的脑袋呢?
Hey, what about Mr. Henderson's head?
没问题?
Okay?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
好吧
Okay.
将军
General.
你是什么人
Who the hell are you?
我就是剩下来的敌人
I'm all that's left of the enemy.
找到了
Bingo.
把手放下
Stand easy.
我还以为自己是老兵
Thought I'd been in the service a long time.
姓名和军阶  水手
Name and rank, sailor.
事实上我是陆军
Well, it's army, actually.
回答问题  并且尊称他为"将军"
Answer the question. And address him as "General, sir."
将军...约翰·梅森上尉  隶属于英国皇家特种部队
Captain John Patrick Mason, General, sir...of Her Majesty's S.A.S.
当然  已经退伍了
Retired, of course.
你离家稍微远了点  上尉
You're a long way from home, Captain.
你是怎么与此事牵扯上的?
How the hell are you involved in this?
我对这座监狱相当熟悉
Oh, I have a unique knowledge of this prison facility.
我以前曾在这里作过客
I was, uh, formerly a guest here.
小家伙
Hi, sweetie.
给我回来  小男孩
Hey, come back here, little boy.
他们有没有告诉你我的目的?
Did they bother to tell you who I am, why I'm doing this?
还是只是利用你而已?
Or are they just using you like they do everybody else?
我只知道电视上说你是个越战英雄
All I know is you were big in Vietnam. I saw the highlights on television.
那你根本就不知道  看到优秀军人...
Then you wouldn't have any fuckin' idea what it means to lead some of the finest men...
被他们的政府出卖的痛苦
on God's earth into battle, and then see their memory betrayed by their own fuckin' government.
我看不出屠杀一百万人...
I don't quite see how you cherish the memory of the dead...
如何能安慰他们的英灵
by killing another million.
而且这不是战争
And, uh, this is not combat.
这是疯狂行径  将军
It's an act of lunacy, General, sir.
我认为你是个大白痴
Personally, I think you're a fuckin' idiot.
"自由之树须以爱国者和暴君的血灌溉开花"
"The tree of liberty must be refreshed from time to time with the blood of patriots and tyrants."
汤玛士杰佛逊说的
Thomas Jefferson.
王尔德说过"爱国主义是邪恶的美德"
"Patriotism is the virtue of the vicious," according to Oscar Wilde.
谢谢你证明我的观点
Thank you for making my point.
导航晶片呢?
Where are the guidance chips?
我毁掉了
I destroyed them.
你不该这么做的
That was a bad move, soldier.
那你要处决我们吗?
Does that mean you'll execute us both?
算你走运  汉默要抓活的
You're lucky that old man Hummel wants you alive.
我倒很乐意把你开膛剖肚
Cause I'll take pleasure in guttin' you, boy.
距离时限五十二分钟
我倒很乐意把你开膛剖肚
I'd take pleasure in guttin' you Boy
"I'll take pleasure in guttin' you, boy."
这些人是怎么了?  梅森?
What is wrong with these people, huh, Mason?
这岛上到处都充满了愤怒
Don't you think there's a lot of, uh, a lot of anger floatin' around this island?
一大堆莽撞青少年
Kind of a pubescent volatility? Don't you think?
你不认为他们满怀苦恼  心中都充满了杀父情结?
A lot of angst, a lot of, " I'm 16, I'm angry at my father" syndrome?
成熟点吧!  我们...
I mean, grow up! We're stuck on an island...
跟一群噬血如命的变态军人混在一起
with a bunch of violence-for-pleasure-seeking psychopathic marines.
他们真丢脸!
Shame on them!
我只拆除了一枚导弹  还剩两枚没拆
Anyway, I only got one chem round. There's two left.
梅森?
Mason?
我在这儿
Yes, I'm here.
我真怀念...
I was just thinking how wonderful it was...
那些不准说话的日子
when the inmates weren't allowed to talk in here.
不准说话?
Not allowed to talk.
你怎么受的了?
How'd you do it?
我在心里满怀希望
Uh, nurtured the hope that there was hope.
希望有一天能重获自由
That one day I'd breathe free air.
也许还能见到我的女儿
Perhaps meet my daughter.
希望很卑微  却能让人保持求生意志
Modest hopes, but, uh, they kept a man alive.
你为什么会被关起来?
What'd they put you away for, John?
说来话长
Oh, that's a long story.
反正我哪里也去不成
Well, I'm not goin' anywhere.
我们的人有多久没有回音了?
When was the last communication from our men on Alcatraz?
七个小时
Seven hours.
铝热剂完成了
Thermite plasma is operational.
帮我接总统
Get me the president.
请坐  请各位保持随时待命
Be seated. Gentlemen, consider yourselves on ground alert. If we receive launch authority...
一旦出发  你们的任务就是彻底摧毁恶魔岛
your mission is the complete thermal destruction of Alcatraz Island.
每一寸地都必须完全摧毁  不能有任何漏失
The entire island is to be blanketed, not one square inch missed.
81名平民以及部份军人...
Eighty-one American civilians and a number of U.S. Marines...
将会在这次攻击中牺牲
will lose their lives in this air strike.
你何不交出胶片...
Why didn't you just tell them where the microfilm was...
问题不就解决了?
and, and create a solution?
一旦胶片拿到手  他们就会让我死
Hmph. The moment they had the microfilm, they'd suicide me.
这是他们的解决办法
Some solution.
结果你被关在这儿
And you ended up here.
这让我想到另一个问题  当年你...
Which brings me to another question. When you broke out...
逃狱的时候我干脆直说吧...
Let me see if I can get this straight. You went down the incinerator chute...
你当年下到焚化炉...滑运道..坐上矿坑小车
on the mine cars, through the tunnels...
穿过隧道到达发电厂
to the power plant.
再穿过蒸气引擎...那招真的很帅...
under the steam engine... That was really cool, by the way...
进入贮水池然后从水管逃出去
and into the cistern through the intake pipe.
不过你到底是...
But how, in the name of Zeus's butthole...
怎么逃出牢房的?
did you get out of your cell?
我之所以问是因为我们目前的处境...
I only ask because in our current situation...
这招应该会很有用!
well, it could prove to be useful information, maybe!
职业秘密  孩子
Trade secrets, my son.
将军  我们只剩两枚可用的导弹
General, two operational rockets left.
一枚在灯塔  一枚在屋顶
One's at the lower lighthouse and there is one on the roof.
都随时待命了  长官
And both of the birds are ready to fly, sir.
将军  你听到吗?
G-General, can you hear me?
我听到了  上尉
I heard you, Captain.
我只想确定一下
Oh, just makin' sure.
我们是否该准备发射了?  将军?
Should we prepare for launch, General?
我来决定战略  上尉
I'll handle the strategy, Captain.
我懂了
Yes, sir.
时间快到了
The hour is approaching, sir.
我只想让你知道这点  长官
Just letting the General know of the time, sir.
这点我很清楚  上尉
I'm very aware of the time, Captain.
是的  长官  只是要让你知道
Aye, aye, sir. Lettin' you know.
弟兄们都准备大干一场
Me and my boys are ready to cock, lock, and ready to rock.
梅森  你要上哪儿去?
Mason, where're you going?
三十年前我就发誓绝不能死在这里
Thirty years ago I vowed I wouldn't die in this toilet.
你不能走!
You're not leaving!
那个狂人手里正操纵着导弹的发射按钮!
There's a madman in there with his hand on a, on a button!
他会被狙击手一枪打死的
Shh. Some sniper's gonna get his ass.
站住  梅森
Stop moving, Mason.
梅森  别动
Mason, stop moving.
汉默不会下手的  他是个军人  不是个谋杀犯
Hummel won't do it. He's a soldier, not a murderer.
我从他的眼神看得出来
I read it in his eyes.
你从他的眼神看得出来?
You read his eyes?
那敢情好!
Oh, well, then, everything's just fine!
我不能冒这个险
I can't afford to take that chance.
拜托你再大声点
Why don't you talk louder?
还剩三分钟  长官
Three minutes to go, sir.
-他们不会打电话来了  -它们会的
-They're not gonna call, Frank.  -Oh, they'll call.
我们发射一枚导弹他们就会打来的
They'll call if we fire one of our rockets up their ass.
我是汉默
Hummel.
法兰克  我是克拉玛
Hi, Frank. It's Al Kramer here.
怎么样?
How's it going out there?
你认为呢?
How do you think it's goin'?
听着  我们还需要一小时
Listen, on this end we're gonna need another hour, Frank.
你们只剩三分钟
You've got three minutes.
法兰克  我们得等总统
Listen, uh, Frank, we have to get final authorization from the president.
你们只有三分钟
You've got three minutes.
法兰克  请你别做傻事
Frank, please don't do anything stupid.
他们还需要一个小时
They want another hour.
鬼扯  他们在骗人!  将军
Well, that's bullshit. That's bullshit, General. They're lyin'!
他们在耍你
They're calling our bluff, sir.
把你当白痴  长官
They're playing you for a fool, sir.
下令发射导弹  将军
Order the launch, General.
快点  将军
Come on, General.
我们下定决心吧!
Let's be all we can be.
任务还没完成!
The mission's not complete!
我的任务完成了
Well, mine is.
这个任务结束之后你会回家...
When this is over, you'll go back home...
开着你的棕色富豪轿车  把卡拉和小宝宝逼疯
driving Carla and your baby insane in your beige Volvo.
我不是死了就是回到监狱  那都没什么两样
And I'll be dead or back in prison, which is the same thing.
你不能走
You're not leaving.
好吧  我自己来
All right, I'll do it myself.
我受过三星期武器训练
I got three weeks' weapons training.
我能消灭...整排海陆
I'll kick the... Out of a platoon full of marines.
小意思
No problem.
-少校  将我连接上屋顶的导弹  -是  长官
-Major, patch me into Roof Battery.  -Aye, sir.
打开控制电路  准备接收目标方位
Fire open control circuit coordinates to the roof, sir.
快点!
Let's go!
启动电源
Laser powered up!
不好
Oh, no.
我说  给我跪下!
I said, on your knees!
我的名字叫史丹利古斯比
My name's Stanley Goodspeed.
我是FBI的化学武器专家
I'm a chemical weapons specialist for the FBI.
玻璃瓮还是塑胶袋?
Uh, glass or plastic?
什么?
What?
玻璃瓮还是塑胶袋?
Glass or plastic? Glass or plastic?
闭嘴!
Shut the fuck up!
因为如果导弹发射后风向改变的话...
Because if the winds change after you launch those rockets...
-我们都会死  -闭嘴!
-we're all gonna die.  -Shut up!
你的尸体不是用玻璃瓮就是用塑胶袋装
And you're gonna end up in either a glass jar or a plastic bag.
你自己想想看  把枪交给我...
So, what do you say you do the math, h-hand over the gun...
我们去找导弹吧?
and let's go find some rockets?
我叫你闭嘴...
I said shut the fuck...
你的选择是对的
You made the right choice.
我决定不让你的孩子...
I decided I didn't want your child...
没有父亲伴他成长
growing up without a father.
我上回游到对岸的时候年龄跟你差不多
Hey, the last time I swam this channel I was your age.
我现在怎么做都是一样  来吧
So, I'm fucked either way. So, come on.
导弹已经就绪  我在等待发射指令
Weapon is hot. I am standing by for the launch command.
杀死特遣队是一回事...
Man, killing Navy SEALs is one thing...
但我们真的要这样做吗?
Is this for real?
只是公事公办
Hey, it's business.
输入密码  准备发射导弹
Access code entered. Weapon available for release.
座标  6  7...
Launch coordinates: Six, seven...
5  4  5  9
five, four, five, niner.
导弹已经就绪  我在等待发射指令
The weapon is hot. I'm standing by for launch command.
我知道了
That's affirmative.
等待指令
Standing by for command.
我在等发射命令
I'm waiting for launch command, General.
-发射  -发射!
-Fire.  -Fire!
导弹升空!  导弹升空!
Missile loose! Missile loose!
恶魔岛  座标67253725
Origin: Alcatraz, 67253725.
-方向?  -南南东185度
-What's the goddamn heading?  -Heading 185 degrees south southeast.
速度?
Speed?
300海里  飞向奥克兰市
Three hundred knots. It's headed right at Oakland.
美式足球赛
Football game.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
导弹完全改变方向
Missile radically changing direction.
目标放弃
新方向  西方275度
New direction: 275 degrees west.
那是飞向海中  长官
It's headed out to sea, sir.
天啊!
Oh, Christ!
导弹正在下降
Missile losing altitude. Falling.
继续下降300尺...200...100
Falling, 300 feet, 200, 100.
导弹在水里引爆了
Bogey detonated under water.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
没射中
It missed.
-太好了  -当然
-Well, that's great.  -Extremely great.
可是还有一枚
But there's still one left.
导弹是怎么回事?  座标怎么会变?
What happened to the rocket? What the fuck happened to the coordinates?
到底是怎么回事?  长官!  少校!
What the fuck is going on? Sir! Major!
-上尉  请你出去  -告诉我  长官
-Captain, step outside.  -Talk to me, sir.
上尉  请你出去!
Captain, step outside!
帮我接五角大厦
Get me the Pentagon.
那算什么?  法兰克?
What the hell was that, Frank?
-我说  那算...-我听到你说的了!
-I said, what the hell...  -I heard what you said!
就算你想犯上  也请你放尊重点
If you're gonna be insubordinate. I'd appreciate it if you'd do it with a little more respect.
废话少说  将军
Cut the crap, General.
-你在干什么?  -我还不想伤害无辜百姓
-What the hell are you doing?  -I'm not ready to kill these people.
打电话给五角大厦  再向他们争取时间
Call the Pentagon. Ask for more time.
不
No!
快点  法兰克!  我们就快失控了
Do it, Frank! We're coming loose.
你才失控了  其他人还是很冷静的
You're coming loose. The rest of us are in complete control.
我们要新的时限
We're askin' 'em. We're askin' 'em for a new deadline.
放下电话
Put the phone down.
-兄弟们开始失控了  -他们是陆战队员!
-The men are falling apart.  -The men are marines!
是吗?
Are they?
-我找克拉玛将军  -我以老朋友的身份劝你
-I wanna talk to General Kramer.  -You've been asked by an old friend.
-现在就打电话给他  -我以上司的身份命令你
-Put him on the phone right now.  -You've been ordered by a superior officer.
我是巴斯特少校
This is Major Baxter.
我给你最后一次机会
Now you're being given your last chance by a man with a gun.
把电话放下
Put the phone down.
我以为你还没准备杀人
I thought you weren't ready to kill.
我开始准备了
I'm warmin' up.
稍息
At ease.
你得做出决定  总统先生
They need a decision, Mr. President.
过去这几个小时...
These past few hours...
是我生命中最漫长  最黑暗的时刻
have been the longest, darkest of my life.
人命该如何衡量呢?
How does one weigh human life?
一百万市民和81名人质
One million civilians against 81 hostages.
还有法兰克·汉默
And in the middle, Frank Hummel.
我们忽视并遗弃像汉默这样伟大的英雄
That we have ignored, abandoned or marginalized a great soldier like Frank Hummel...
还有那些被忽视且为国捐驱的军人子弟...
and that American boys have paid for that neglect in blood...
同样地真实  也同样地悲哀
is equally real and equally tragic.
我们向恐怖行动宣战
We are at war with terror.
战争必有伤亡
Fighting a war means casualties.
这是我所做过最困难的决定
This is the worst call I've ever had to make.
批准空袭行动
Air strike approved.
红雷  准备起飞
Red Thunder to tower. Request clearance.
投下这么多的弹药...
With the amount of firepower they're gonna drop in there...
塔台  准备起飞
Tower this is Strike Leader. Prepared to go.
几秒就会完全毁灭
It'll be over in a few seconds.
十七分钟后抵达目标
Flight time to drop point: 17 minutes.
对不起  将军  恕我无理
Excuse me, General, sir, with all due respect to you.
你倒底在搞什么鬼?
But what the fuck is going on?
你更改了座标  是不是  将军?
You changed the coordinates, didn't you, General?
没错  上尉
That's affirmative, Captain.
现在他们以为我们没种  因为我们什么都没做到
So, now they think we're gutless, the Feds? They think we won't actually do it.
他们会从海上与空中全力进攻
They're gonna come at us with everything they've got. Air and sea.
把我们炸的粉身碎骨
They're gonna bomb our ass back to the Stone Age.
他们不知道我们是故意错开目标的
They don't know we missed on purpose.
太好了  我们不是没种  而是无能
Great. We're not gutless, we're incompetent.
对吧?
That right?
我不喜欢你的口气  上尉
I don't think I like your tone, Captain. We planned for this contingency.
带导弹和四名人质撤退
Load the V.X. Into the choppers, take four hostages and evacuate.
我会留下来承担一切后果
The consequences of our actions I'll face alone.
对不起  将军  他妈的钱呢?
Excuse me, General, but what about the fucking money?
没有钱  任务结束
There is no fucking money. Mission's over.
放屁
Bullshit it's over.
你在跟一位将军讲话  维持军纪
You're talking to a General, soldier. Maintain discipline.
我不是军人  少校
I'm not a soldier, Major.
在我们挟持人质之后  我们就成了佣兵
The day we took hostages we became mercenaries.
佣兵要的是钱!
And mercenaries get paid!
我要我的钱!
I want my fucking money!
这项任务全靠武力威胁
This mission was based on the threat of force.
我不会屠杀八万无辜百姓  你以为我疯了吗?
I'm not about to kill 80,000 innocent people. Do you think I'm out of my fucking mind?
我们虚张声势  他们发现了
We bluffed. They called it.
任务结束
The mission's over.
谁说我们是虚张声势的  将军?
Whoever said anything about bluffing, General?
退下  上尉
Stand down, Captain.
退下  上尉!
Stand down, Captain!
少校  我要你带着这些人上直升机  准备撤退
Major, I'm ordering you to take these men to the choppers and evacuate.
我的命令很简单  少校!
That's a simple order, Major!
一点都不简单  法兰克
It's not so simple, Frank.
柯中士...
Sergeant Crisp...
逮捕将军
secure the General.
我解除你的指挥权  长官
I'm relieving you of your command, sir.
中士!
Sergeant!
-请把手枪给我  长官  -你是说这把吗?
-I'll have that sidearm, sir.  -You mean this sidearm?
少校  你站在哪一边?
Major Baxter, you're either with us or against us.
我很荣幸能跟你一起服役  将军
It has been the greatest honor of my life to serve with you, General.
可是就像他说的...
But like he said...
一切都结束了
it's over.
我们去救他
Let's get him.
梅森!
Mason!
我的天啊  我做了什么?
My God, what have I done?
还有一枚导弹呢?
Where's the last rocket?
最后一枚导弹呢?
灯塔
Lower lighthouse.
-灯塔  -快去!
-Lower lighthouse.  Go!
快去灯塔  我来解决这个混蛋!
Darrow, go to the lighthouse. I'll take care of this fucker!
一  二  三  吃颗这个吧!
One, two, three! Eat that!
搞定了
Did it.
别乱来
Come here.
过来  过来  你这孬种
Come here, you little chicken shit!
你开枪打我  我就丢下这个  我们两个都死定了
You shoot me, I drop this. We're both dead.
别害怕  我不会伤害你的
Well, come on. Come on. Don't be scared. I won't hurt ya.
-来吧  -你知道这玩意的厉害吗?
-Come on.  -Do you know how this shit works?
你知道这玩意的厉害吗?
You know how this shit works?
来吧
Come on. Come on.
我不用枪  我放下来
I don't need the gun. I'll put it down.
来吧  咱们来玩玩
Come on. Let's play. Come on. Come on.
我们之间有点误解
Listen, I think we got started off on the wrong foot.
我是史丹利·古斯比  联邦探员...
Stan Goodspeed, FBI. Uh...
我们谈谈音乐吧
Let's talk music.
你喜欢艾尔顿强的"火箭人"吗?
Do you like the Elton John song, "Rocket Man"?
我不听靡靡之音
I don't like soft-ass shit.
噢...
Oh, you... Oh, oh. Oh.
我只是想说  是你
Well, I only bring it up because, uh, it's you.
你就是"火箭人"
You're the Rocket Man.
不!
No!
很过瘾吧?
How do you like how that shit works?
第二枚导弹升空!
Second rocket's away!
沉入海底  没有引爆
It splashed into the bay, sir. No detonation.
他妈的
Shit!
戴洛!
Darrow!
把门打开!
Open up!
快点
Come on.
快打开!
Open up!
我看到了!
Hey, you mother!
来点刺激的吧  宝贝
Oh, I'm gonna get you now, baby.
我瞄准你了
I got ya. I got you, baby.
来吧
Come on.
混蛋!
Fucker!
红雷攻击小组队长
Red Thunder Strike Leader.
七分钟后抵达目标
Time on target: Seven minutes.
英国佬
English prick.
告诉你  我老子是爱尔兰人
I tell you my old man was Irish?
时速450海浬
Maintain air speed 450 knots.
干!
Fuck!
只剩下我们了  朋友
It's me and you, pal.
晶片呢?
I want that fucking chip!
我最爱压力
I love pressure.
我知道你在里头  我知道你听得到我说话
I know you're in here, and I know you can hear me.
快点  有种就出来
Now, pay the piper and come out like a man.
加速到500海浬
Increase speed to 500 knots.
臭小子!  去死吧!
You motherfucker! Die!
你害我拿不到一百万  你去死吧!
I'm gonna choke my million bucks out of you. You're gonna die. Eat that, you fuck!
六十秒后抵达目标
All right, team, inbound. Time on target: 60 seconds.
方向142度
Come to course heading 142 degrees.
你们解除毒气导弹之后...
When he neutralizes the threat...
发射绿色信号弹并等待救援
we launch green flares and we wait for the cavalry.
成紧密编队
Let's tighten up that formation.
愿上帝怜悯他们的灵魂
May God have mercy on your souls.
别这么做  快想想其他办法
Please don't let this happen. There has to be something you can do. Please.
下降至雷达范围一百尺下
Let's drop to the deck. One hundred feet below radar.
锁定目标  接近中
Target acquired. Rolling in.
开启按钮  开启按钮
This is Red Thunder. Master armed. Master armed.
12秒后抵达目标
Time on target: 12 seconds.
10秒
T.O. T: Ten seconds.
紧密编队  各位
Stay tight, gentlemen.
我看到绿烟!  我看到绿烟!
I got green smoke. I got green smoke!
这里是CQ1!  我们看到绿烟了!  完毕
This is C.Q. One, C.Q. One! Green smoke! We have green smoke! Over.
给我!  放弃!
Eh, gimme that!  Gimme that! Abort!
队长  放弃任务!
Flight leader, abort, abort, abort!
天啊...
Jesus Chri...
我已经投下炸弹了!
I already dropped them!
-该死!  -我的天啊!
-Oh, goddamn it!  -Oh, my God!
让开  让我过去  让我过去!
Get out of my way. Let me through, please. Let me through!
监狱无损  只炸毁小岛后方
The cells did not get hit. The bombs hit on the back of the island.
我不想再救你了  你真是走运
I'm fed up saving your ass. I'm amazed you ever got past puberty.
这是你孩子最精彩的床边故事
I suppose all this will make a great bedtime story to tell your kid.
我说  梅森  他们会做恶梦
You're insane, Mason. The kid'll have nightmares.
还得花一大笔钱去看心理医生
Spend all my money on shrinks.
古斯比  你听得到吗?
Goodspeed, come in.
古斯比  古斯比  你听得到吗?  请回答!
Goodspeed, Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in!
扫描所有频道
Scanning all radio frequencies.
古斯比  你听得到吗?  请回答!
Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in!
我是古斯比
This is Goodspeed.
人质还活着吗?
Are the hostages alive?
全都活着
Every one of 'em.
古斯比  我是沃麦  梅森呢?
Goodspeed, it's Womack. What about Mason?
他死了  长官
He's dead, sir.
怎么死的?  何时死的?
How? When?
快来接我
Just come and get me.
沃麦撕掉你的赦免令  约翰
Womack tore up your pardon, John.
当然  我早知他会如此
But, of course. I knew he would.
潜水的机器应该还在我们上岸的地方
The S.D.U. S and the scuba gear should still be where we came ashore.
旧金山泛亚饭店  我的衣橱里有衣服...
If you can get to the Pan Pacific Hotel, there's clothes in my closet...
圣经里藏有两百块
$200 in the Bible.
26号房
Room 26.
我很久都没向人道谢了
Well, it's been a long time since I've said thank you to anybody.
谢谢你
But thank you.
史丹利  我们该分手了
Well, Stanley, uh, this is when we go our separate ways, huh?
我相信你一定知道  你的名字所隐含的意义
But, uh, I'm sure you know the etymology of your name "Goodspeed."
"GODSPEED"  祝人旅途上一路平安
Yeah, Godspeed: To wish someone a prosperous journey. Why?
如果你想去旅行...
Well, if you fancy a journey...
我建议你去堪萨斯州的华顿堡
I recommend Fort Walton, Kansas.
我想去茂伊岛
I was thinking of Maui.
别去茂伊岛
Forget Maui.
堪州华顿堡圣弥迦教堂
"St. Michael's Church, Fort Walton, Kansas.
前排  右椅腿  空心
"Front pew, right leg. Hollow."
是不是那玩意?
Is this what I think it is?
梅森?
Mason?
恭喜你  古斯比博士  你成功了
Congratulations, Dr. Goodspeed. You did it.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, sir.
你知道吗  有一阵子我还以为你死定了
You know, for a while there, I didn't think you were gonna make it.
干得好  孩子
Well done, son.
梅森呢?
So, where's Mason?
被蒸发了
Vaporized.
被吹到海上
Blown out to sea.
被吹到海上?
Blown out to sea, huh?
没错
Yeah.
可怜的傢伙
Poor bastard.
古斯比  梅森呢?  他的尸体呢?  我要看看那个狗娘养的!
Goodspeed, where's Mason? Where's his body? I wanna see that son of a bitch!
他被蒸发了  长官
Vaporized, sir.
失陪了  各位
Excuse me, gentlemen.
什么?  蒸发?  尸体能够被蒸发掉?
What? Vaporized? A body can vaporize?
当然能!  长官
Oh, yeah! Absolutely, sir.
圣弥迦教堂  前排  右椅腿
St. Michael's Church, front pew, right leg.
前排  右椅腿
Front pew, right leg.
小偷  小偷
Vandals! Vandals!
宝贝  快来!
Oh, yes, baby, come on!
站住!  小偷!  站住!
Stop! Vandals! Stop!
对不起!
I'm sorry!
快点  宝贝!
Come on, baby!
拿到了!  快走!
I've got it! Okay, let's go!
-站住!-对不起!
-Stop! Stop!  -Sorry!
站住!
Stop! Hey, hey, you!
小偷!
Vandals! Vandals!
亲爱的...
Honey, uh...
你想知道是谁杀了肯尼迪吗?
you wanna know who really killed J.F.K?